{
  "courseName": "Minna no Nihongo 1 & 2",
  "description": "Lessons 1-50 vocabulary and expressions",
  "items": [
    {
      "front": "わたし",
      "reading": "I",
      "back": "わたし",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "あなた",
      "reading": "You",
      "back": "あなた",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "あの　ひと　（あの　かた）　",
      "reading": "That person, he, she (あの　かた　is the polite equivalent of あの　ひと）",
      "back": "あの　ひと　（あの　かた）",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "～さん",
      "reading": "Mr., Ms. (suffix added to a name for expressing politeness)",
      "back": "~さん",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "～ちゃん",
      "reading": "(suffix often added to a child:s name instead of ~san)",
      "back": "~ちゃん",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "～人",
      "reading": "(suffix meaning `a national of`)",
      "back": "~ 人[じん]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "先生",
      "reading": "teacher, instructor (not used when referring to one`s own job)",
      "back": "先生[せんせい]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "教師",
      "reading": "teacher, instructor",
      "back": "教師[きょうし]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "学生",
      "reading": "student",
      "back": "学生[がくせい]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "会社員",
      "reading": "company employee",
      "back": "会社[かいしゃ] 員[いん]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "社員",
      "reading": "employee of ~ company (used with a company`s name)",
      "back": "社員[しゃいん]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "銀行員",
      "reading": "bank employee",
      "back": "銀行[ぎんこう] 員[いん]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "医者",
      "reading": "[medical] doctor",
      "back": "医者[いしゃ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "研究者",
      "reading": "researcher, scholar",
      "back": "研究[けんきゅう] 者[しゃ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "大学",
      "reading": "university",
      "back": "大学[だいがく]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "病院",
      "reading": "hospital",
      "back": "病院[びょういん]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "だれ（どなた）",
      "reading": "who (どなた is the polite equivalent)",
      "back": "だれ（どなた）",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "ーさい",
      "reading": "- years old",
      "back": "ーさい",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "何歳　（おいくつ）",
      "reading": "how old (おいくつ is the polite equivalent)",
      "back": "何[なん] 歳[さい]　（おいくつ）",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "はい",
      "reading": "yes",
      "back": "はい&nbsp;",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "いいえ",
      "reading": "no",
      "back": "いいえ",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "初めまして",
      "reading": "How do you do it? (lit. I am meeting you for the first time. Usually used as the first phrase when introducing oneself.)",
      "back": "初[はじ]めまして",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "～から　来ました。",
      "reading": "I`m from ~ (country).",
      "back": "~から　 来[き]ました。",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "［どうぞ］　よろしく　［お願いします］。",
      "reading": "Pleased to meet you. (lit. Please be nice to me. Usually used at the end of a self-introduction.)",
      "back": "［どうぞ］　よろしく　［お 願[ねが]いします］。",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "失礼ですが",
      "reading": "Excuse me, but (used when asking someone for personal information such as their name or address)",
      "back": "失礼[しつれい]ですが",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "お名前は？",
      "reading": "May I have your name?",
      "back": "お 名前[なまえ]は？",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "こちらは　～さんです。　",
      "reading": "This is Mr./Ms. ~.",
      "back": "こちらは　~さんです。",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "アメリカ",
      "reading": "U.S.A.",
      "back": "アメリカ",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "イギリス",
      "reading": "U.K.",
      "back": "イギリス",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "インド",
      "reading": "India",
      "back": "インド",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "インドネシア",
      "reading": "Indonesia",
      "back": "インドネシア",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "韓国",
      "reading": "South Korea",
      "back": "韓国[かんこく]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "タイ",
      "reading": "Thailand",
      "back": "タイ",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "中国",
      "reading": "China",
      "back": "中国[ちゅうごく]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "ドイツ",
      "reading": "Germany",
      "back": "ドイツ",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "日本",
      "reading": "Japan",
      "back": "日本[にっほん]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "ブラジル",
      "reading": "Brazil",
      "back": "ブラジル",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "これ",
      "reading": "this (thing here)",
      "back": "これ",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "それ",
      "reading": "that (thing near the listener)",
      "back": "それ",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "あれ",
      "reading": "that (thing over there)",
      "back": "あれ",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "この　～",
      "reading": "this ~, this ~ here",
      "back": "この　~",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "その　～",
      "reading": "that ~, that ~ near the listener",
      "back": "その　~",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "あの　～",
      "reading": "that ~, that ~ over there",
      "back": "あの　~",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "本",
      "reading": "book",
      "back": "本[ほん]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "辞書",
      "reading": "dictionary",
      "back": "辞書[じしょ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "雑誌",
      "reading": "magazine",
      "back": "雑誌[ざっし]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "新聞",
      "reading": "newspaper",
      "back": "新聞[しんぶん]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "ノート",
      "reading": "notebook",
      "back": "ノート",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "手帳",
      "reading": "personal organiser",
      "back": "手帳[てちょう]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "名称",
      "reading": "business card",
      "back": "名称[めいし]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "カード",
      "reading": "(credit) card",
      "back": "カード",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "鉛筆",
      "reading": "pencil",
      "back": "鉛筆[えんぴつ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "ボールペン",
      "reading": "ballpoint pen",
      "back": "ボールペン",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "シャープペンシル",
      "reading": "mechanical pencil, propelling pencil",
      "back": "シャープペンシル",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "かぎ",
      "reading": "key",
      "back": "かぎ",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "時計",
      "reading": "watch, clock",
      "back": "時計[とけい]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "傘",
      "reading": "umbrella",
      "back": "傘[かさ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "かばん",
      "reading": "bag, briefcase",
      "back": "かばん",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "CD",
      "reading": "CD, compact disc",
      "back": "CD",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "テルビ",
      "reading": "television",
      "back": "テルビ",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "ラジオ",
      "reading": "radio",
      "back": "ラジオ",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "カメラ",
      "reading": "camera",
      "back": "カメラ",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "コンピューター",
      "reading": "computer",
      "back": "コンピューター",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "車",
      "reading": "car, vehicle",
      "back": "車[くるま]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "机",
      "reading": "desk",
      "back": "机[つくえ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "いす",
      "reading": "chair",
      "back": "いす",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "チョコレート",
      "reading": "chocolate",
      "back": "チョコレート",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "コーヒー",
      "reading": "coffee",
      "back": "コーヒー",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "［お］土産",
      "reading": "souvenir, present",
      "back": "［お］ 土産[みやげ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "英語",
      "reading": "the English language",
      "back": "英語[えいご]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "日本語",
      "reading": "the Japanese language",
      "back": "日本語[にほんご]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "何",
      "reading": "what",
      "back": "何[なん]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "そう",
      "reading": "so",
      "back": "そう",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "あのう。。。",
      "reading": "Er...(used to show hesitation)",
      "back": "あのう。。。",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "えっ",
      "reading": "Oh? What! (used when hearing something unexpected)",
      "back": "えっ",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "どうぞ。",
      "reading": "Here you are. (used when offering someone something)",
      "back": "どうぞ。",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "［どうも］　ありがとう　［ございます］。",
      "reading": "Thank you [very much].",
      "back": "［どうも］　ありがとう　［ございます］。",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "そうですか。",
      "reading": "I see.",
      "back": "そうですか。",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "違います。",
      "reading": "No, it isn`t./You are wrong.",
      "back": "違[ちが]います。",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "あ",
      "reading": "Oh! (used when becoming aware of something)",
      "back": "あ",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "これから　お世話に　なります。",
      "reading": "Thank you in advance for your kindness.",
      "back": "これから　お 世話[せわ]に　なります。",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "こちらこそ　［どうぞ］　よろしく　［お願いします］",
      "reading": "Pleased to meet you, too. (response to ［どうぞ］　よろしく　［お願いします］）",
      "back": "こちらこそ　［どうぞ］　よろしく　［お 願[ねが]いします］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "ここ",
      "reading": "here, this place",
      "back": "ここ",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "そこ",
      "reading": "there, that place near the listener",
      "back": "そこ",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "あそこ",
      "reading": "that place over there",
      "back": "あそこ",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "どこ",
      "reading": "where, what place",
      "back": "どこ",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "こちら",
      "reading": "this way, this place (polite equivalent of ここ）",
      "back": "こちら",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "そちら",
      "reading": "That way, that place near the listener (polite equivalent of そこ）",
      "back": "そちら",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "あちら",
      "reading": "that way, that place over there (polite equivalent of あそこ）",
      "back": "あちら",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "どちら",
      "reading": "which way, where (polite equivalent of どこ）",
      "back": "どちら",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "教室",
      "reading": "classroom",
      "back": "教室[きょうしつ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "食堂",
      "reading": "dining hall, canteen",
      "back": "食堂[しょくどう]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "事務所",
      "reading": "office",
      "back": "事務所[じむしょ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "会議室",
      "reading": "conference room, meeting room",
      "back": "会議[かいぎ] 室[しつ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "受付",
      "reading": "reception desk",
      "back": "受付[うけつけ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "ロビー",
      "reading": "lobby",
      "back": "ロビー",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "部屋",
      "reading": "room",
      "back": "部屋[へや]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "トイレ（お手洗い）",
      "reading": "toilet, rest room",
      "back": "トイレ（お 手洗[てあら]い）",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "かいだん",
      "reading": "staircase",
      "back": "かいだん",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "エレベーター",
      "reading": "lift, elevator",
      "back": "エレベーター",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "エスカレーター",
      "reading": "escalator",
      "back": "エスカレーター",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "自動販売機",
      "reading": "vending machine",
      "back": "自動[じどう] 販売[はんばい] 機[き]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "電話",
      "reading": "telephone handset, telephone call",
      "back": "電話[でんわ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "［お］国",
      "reading": "country",
      "back": "［お］ 国[こく]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "会社",
      "reading": "company",
      "back": "会社[かいしゃ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "うち",
      "reading": "house, home",
      "back": "うち",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "靴",
      "reading": "shoes",
      "back": "靴[くつ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "ネクタイ",
      "reading": "tie, necktie",
      "back": "ネクタイ",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "ワイン",
      "reading": "wine",
      "back": "ワイン",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "売り場",
      "reading": "department, counter (in a department store, etc.)",
      "back": "売り場[うりば]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "地下",
      "reading": "basement",
      "back": "地下[ちか]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "ーかい　（がい）",
      "reading": "-th floor",
      "back": "ーかい　（がい）",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "なんがい",
      "reading": "what floor",
      "back": "なんがい",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "ーえん",
      "reading": "- yen",
      "back": "ーえん",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "いくら",
      "reading": "how much",
      "back": "いくら",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "百",
      "reading": "hundred",
      "back": "百[ひゃく]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "千",
      "reading": "thousand",
      "back": "千[せん]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "万",
      "reading": "ten thousand",
      "back": "万[まん]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "すみません。",
      "reading": "Excuse me.",
      "back": "すみません。",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "どうも。",
      "reading": "Thanks.",
      "back": "どうも。",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "いらっしゃいませ。",
      "reading": "Welcome./May I help you? (a greeting to a customer or a guest entering a shop, etc.)",
      "back": "いらっしゃいませ。",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "［～を］みせて　ください。",
      "reading": "Please show me [~].",
      "back": "［~を］みせて　ください。",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "じゃ",
      "reading": "well, then, in that case.",
      "back": "じゃ",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "［～を］ください。",
      "reading": "Give me [~], please.",
      "back": "［~を］ください。",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "イタリア",
      "reading": "Italy",
      "back": "イタリア",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "スイス",
      "reading": "Switzerland",
      "back": "スイス",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "フランス",
      "reading": "France",
      "back": "フランス",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "ジャカルタ",
      "reading": "Jakarta",
      "back": "ジャカルタ",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "バンコク",
      "reading": "Bangkok",
      "back": "バンコク",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "ベルリン",
      "reading": "Berlin",
      "back": "ベルリン",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "起きます",
      "reading": "get up, wake up",
      "back": "起[お]きます",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "寝ます",
      "reading": "sleep, go to bed",
      "back": "寝[ね]ます",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "働きます",
      "reading": "To work",
      "back": "働[はたら]きます",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "休みます",
      "reading": "To take a rest, take a holiday",
      "back": "休[やす]みます",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "べんきょうします",
      "reading": "To study",
      "back": "べんきょうします",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "終わります",
      "reading": "To finish",
      "back": "終[お]わります",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "デパート",
      "reading": "department store",
      "back": "デパート",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "銀行",
      "reading": "bank",
      "back": "銀行[ぎんこう]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "郵便局",
      "reading": "post office",
      "back": "郵便[ゆうびん] 局[きょく]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "図書館",
      "reading": "library",
      "back": "図書館[としょかん]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "美術館",
      "reading": "art museum, art gallery",
      "back": "美術館[びじゅつかん]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "今",
      "reading": "now",
      "back": "今[いま]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "ーじ",
      "reading": "- o`clock",
      "back": "ーじ",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "（－分）（－ぷん）　",
      "reading": "- minute",
      "back": "（ ー分[ふん]）（ーぷん）",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "半",
      "reading": "half",
      "back": "半[はん]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "何時",
      "reading": "what time",
      "back": "何時[なんじ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "何分",
      "reading": "what minute",
      "back": "何分[なんぷん]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "午前",
      "reading": "a.m., morning",
      "back": "午前[ごぜん]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "午後",
      "reading": "p.m., afternoon",
      "back": "午後[ごご]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "朝",
      "reading": "morning",
      "back": "朝[あさ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "昼",
      "reading": "daytime, noon",
      "back": "昼[ひる]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "ばん　（よる）",
      "reading": "night, evening",
      "back": "ばん　（よる）",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "おととい",
      "reading": "the day before yesterday",
      "back": "おととい",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "きのう",
      "reading": "yesterday",
      "back": "きのう",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "きょう",
      "reading": "today",
      "back": "きょう",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "あした",
      "reading": "tomorrow",
      "back": "あした",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "あさって",
      "reading": "the day after tomorrow",
      "back": "あさって",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "けさ",
      "reading": "this morning",
      "back": "けさ",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "今晩",
      "reading": "this evening, tonight",
      "back": "今晩[こんばん]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "やすみ",
      "reading": "A rest, a holiday, a day off",
      "back": "やすみ",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "昼休み",
      "reading": "lunchtime (lit. noon/afternoon break)",
      "back": "昼休[ひるやす]み",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "試験",
      "reading": "examination, test",
      "back": "試験[しけん]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "会議",
      "reading": "meeting, conference (～を　します：hold a meeting)",
      "back": "会議[かいぎ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "映画",
      "reading": "film, movie",
      "back": "映画[えいが]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "毎朝",
      "reading": "every morning",
      "back": "毎朝[まいあさ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "毎晩",
      "reading": "every night",
      "back": "毎晩[まいばん]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "毎日",
      "reading": "every day",
      "back": "毎日[まいにち]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "月曜日",
      "reading": "Monday",
      "back": "月曜日[げつようび]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "火曜日",
      "reading": "Tuesday",
      "back": "火曜日[かようび]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "水曜日",
      "reading": "Wednesday",
      "back": "水曜日[すいようび]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "木曜日",
      "reading": "Thursday",
      "back": "木曜日[もくようび]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "金曜日",
      "reading": "Friday",
      "back": "金曜日[きんようび]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "土曜日",
      "reading": "Saturday",
      "back": "土曜日[どようび]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "日曜日",
      "reading": "Sunday",
      "back": "日曜日[にちようび]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "何曜日",
      "reading": "what day of the week",
      "back": "何[なん] 曜日[ようび]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "～から",
      "reading": "from ~",
      "back": "〜から",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "～まで",
      "reading": "up to ~, until ~",
      "back": "~まで",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "～と～",
      "reading": "and (used to connect nouns)",
      "back": "~と~",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "たいへんですね。",
      "reading": "That's tough isn't it? (used when expressing sympathy)",
      "back": "たいへんですね。",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "ばんごう",
      "reading": "number",
      "back": "ばんごう",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "なんばん",
      "reading": "what number",
      "back": "なんばん",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "ニューヨーク",
      "reading": "New York",
      "back": "ニューヨーク",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "ペキン　（北京）",
      "reading": "Beijing",
      "back": "ペキン　（ 北京[ぺきん]）",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "ロサンゼルス",
      "reading": "Los Angeles",
      "back": "ロサンゼルス",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "ロンドン",
      "reading": "London",
      "back": "ロンドン",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "行きます",
      "reading": "To go",
      "back": "行[い]きます",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "来ます",
      "reading": "To come",
      "back": "来[き]ます",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "帰ります",
      "reading": "To go home, return",
      "back": "帰[かえ]ります",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "学校",
      "reading": "school",
      "back": "学校[がっこう]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "スーパー",
      "reading": "supermarket",
      "back": "スーパー",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "駅",
      "reading": "station",
      "back": "駅[えき]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "飛行機",
      "reading": "airplane",
      "back": "飛行機[ひこうき]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "船",
      "reading": "ship",
      "back": "船[ふね]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "電車",
      "reading": "electric train",
      "back": "電車[でんしゃ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "地下鉄",
      "reading": "underground, subway",
      "back": "地下鉄[ちかてつ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "新幹線",
      "reading": "the Shinkansen, the bullet train",
      "back": "新幹線[しんかんせん]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "バス",
      "reading": "bus",
      "back": "バス",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "タクシー",
      "reading": "taxi",
      "back": "タクシー",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "自転車",
      "reading": "bicycle",
      "back": "自転車[じてんしゃ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "歩いて",
      "reading": "on foot",
      "back": "歩[ある]いて",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "人",
      "reading": "person, people",
      "back": "人[ひと]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "友達",
      "reading": "friend",
      "back": "友達[ともだち]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "彼",
      "reading": "he, boyfriend, lover",
      "back": "彼[かれ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "彼女",
      "reading": "she, girlfriend, lover",
      "back": "彼女[かのじょ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "家族",
      "reading": "family",
      "back": "家族[かぞく]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "一人で",
      "reading": "alone, by oneself",
      "back": "一 人[ひとり]で",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "先週",
      "reading": "Last week",
      "back": "先週[せんしゅう]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "今週",
      "reading": "this week",
      "back": "今週[こんしゅう]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "来週",
      "reading": "next week",
      "back": "来週[らいしゅう]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "先月",
      "reading": "last month",
      "back": "先月[せんげつ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "今月",
      "reading": "this month",
      "back": "今月[こんげつ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "来月",
      "reading": "next month",
      "back": "来月[らいげつ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "去年",
      "reading": "last year",
      "back": "去年[きょねん]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "ことし",
      "reading": "this year",
      "back": "ことし",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "来年",
      "reading": "next year",
      "back": "来年[らいねん]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "ー寝",
      "reading": "-th year",
      "back": "ー 寝[ねん]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "何年",
      "reading": "what year",
      "back": "何[なん] 年[ねん]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "－月",
      "reading": "-th month of the year",
      "back": "月[がつ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "何月",
      "reading": "what month",
      "back": "何[なん] 月[がつ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "ついたち　（1日）",
      "reading": "first day of the month",
      "back": "ついたち　（ 1 日）",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "二日",
      "reading": "The second, two days",
      "back": "二[ふつ]日[か]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "三日",
      "reading": "third, three days",
      "back": "三[みっ] 日[か]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "四日",
      "reading": "fourth, four days",
      "back": "四[よっ] 日[か]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "五日",
      "reading": "fifth, five days",
      "back": "五[いつ]日[か]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "六日",
      "reading": "six, six days",
      "back": "六[むい]日[か]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "七日",
      "reading": "seventh, seven days",
      "back": "七[なの]日[か]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "八日",
      "reading": "eigth, eight days",
      "back": "八[よう] 日[か]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "九日",
      "reading": "ninth, nine days",
      "back": "九[ここの]日[か]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "十日",
      "reading": "tenth, ten days",
      "back": "十[とう]日[か]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "十四日",
      "reading": "fourteenth, fourteen days",
      "back": "十[じゅう]四[よっ]日[か]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "廿日",
      "reading": "twentieth, twenty days",
      "back": "廿[はつ] 日[か]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "二十四日",
      "reading": "twenty-fourth, twenty-four days",
      "back": "二[に]十[じゅう]四[よっ]日[か]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "－日",
      "reading": "-th day of the month, - day(s)",
      "back": "日[にち]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "何日",
      "reading": "which day of the month, how many days",
      "back": "何[なん] 日[にち]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "いつ",
      "reading": "when",
      "back": "いつ",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "誕生日",
      "reading": "birthday",
      "back": "誕生[たんじょう] 日[び]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "そうですね。",
      "reading": "Yes, it is.",
      "back": "そうですね。",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "［どうも］ありがとう　ございました。",
      "reading": "Thank you very much for what you did.",
      "back": "［どうも］ありがとう　ございました。",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "どう　いたしまして。",
      "reading": "You're welcome. / Don't mention it.",
      "back": "どう　いたしまして。",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "ー番線",
      "reading": "platform -, -th platform",
      "back": "ー 番線[ばんせん]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "次の",
      "reading": "next",
      "back": "次[つぎ]の",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "普通",
      "reading": "local (train)",
      "back": "普通[ふつう]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "急行",
      "reading": "rapid",
      "back": "急行[きゅうこう]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "特急",
      "reading": "express",
      "back": "特急[とっきゅう]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "大阪城",
      "reading": "Osaka Castle, a famous castle in Osaka",
      "back": "大阪城[おおさかじょう]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "食べます",
      "reading": "To eat",
      "back": "食[た]べます",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "飲みます",
      "reading": "to drink",
      "back": "飲[の]みます",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "吸います［たばこを～］",
      "reading": "To smoke [a cigarette]",
      "back": "吸[す]います［たばこを~］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "見ます",
      "reading": "To see, look at, watch",
      "back": "見[み]ます",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "聞きます",
      "reading": "To hear, listen",
      "back": "聞[き]きます",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "読みます",
      "reading": "To read",
      "back": "読[よ]みます",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "書きます",
      "reading": "To write (かきます　can also mean to draw or paint, but in this case it is written with hirigana in this book)",
      "back": "書[か]きます",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "買います",
      "reading": "To buy",
      "back": "買[か]います",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "取ります　［写真を～］",
      "reading": "To take [a photograph]",
      "back": "取[と]ります　［ 写真[しゃしん]を~］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "します",
      "reading": "To do, play",
      "back": "します",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "会います　［友達に〜］",
      "reading": "To meet [a friend]",
      "back": "会[あ]います　［ 友達[ともだち]に〜］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "ごはん",
      "reading": "a meal, cooked rice",
      "back": "ごはん",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "朝ごはん",
      "reading": "breakfast",
      "back": "朝[あさ]ごはん",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "昼ごはん",
      "reading": "lunch",
      "back": "昼[ひる]ごはん",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "晩ごはん",
      "reading": "dinner, supper",
      "back": "晩[ばん]ごはん",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "パン",
      "reading": "bread",
      "back": "パン",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "卵",
      "reading": "egg",
      "back": "卵[たまご]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "肉",
      "reading": "meat",
      "back": "肉[にく]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "魚",
      "reading": "fish",
      "back": "魚[さかな]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "野菜",
      "reading": "vegetable",
      "back": "野菜[やさい]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "果物",
      "reading": "fruit",
      "back": "果物[くだもの]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "[お] 水",
      "reading": "water",
      "back": "[お] 水[みず]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "お茶",
      "reading": "tea, green tea",
      "back": "お 茶[ちゃ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "紅茶",
      "reading": "black tea",
      "back": "紅茶[こうちゃ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "牛乳（ミルク）",
      "reading": "milk",
      "back": "牛乳[ぎゅうにゅう]（ミルク）",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "ジュース",
      "reading": "juice",
      "back": "ジュース",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "ビール",
      "reading": "beer",
      "back": "ビール",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "［お］酒",
      "reading": "alcohol, Japanese rice wine",
      "back": "［お］ 酒[さけ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "たばこ",
      "reading": "tobacco, cigarette",
      "back": "たばこ",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "手紙",
      "reading": "letter",
      "back": "手紙[てがみ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "レポート",
      "reading": "report",
      "back": "レポート",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "写真",
      "reading": "photograph",
      "back": "写真[しゃしん]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "ビデオ",
      "reading": "video [tape], video deck",
      "back": "ビデオ",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "店",
      "reading": "shop, store",
      "back": "店[みせ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "庭",
      "reading": "garden",
      "back": "庭[にわ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "宿題",
      "reading": "homework (～を　します：do homework)",
      "back": "宿題[しゅくだい]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "テニス",
      "reading": "tennis (～を　します：play tennis)",
      "back": "テニス",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "サッカー",
      "reading": "soccer, football (～を　します：play soccer)",
      "back": "サッカー",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "［お］花見",
      "reading": "cherry-blossom viewing (～を　します：view the cherry blossoms)",
      "back": "［お］ 花見[はなみ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "いっしょに",
      "reading": "together",
      "back": "いっしょに",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "ちょっと",
      "reading": "a little while, a little bit",
      "back": "ちょっと",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "いつも",
      "reading": "always, usually",
      "back": "いつも",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "時々",
      "reading": "sometimes",
      "back": "時々[ときどき]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "それから",
      "reading": "after then, and then",
      "back": "それから",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "いいですね。",
      "reading": "That's good.",
      "back": "いいですね。",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "わかりました。",
      "reading": "I see, I understood.",
      "back": "わかりました。",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "何ですか。",
      "reading": "Yes? (lit. What is it?)",
      "back": "何[なん]ですか。",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "じゃ、また［あした］。",
      "reading": "See you [tomorrow].",
      "back": "じゃ、また［あした］。",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "メキシコ",
      "reading": "Mexico",
      "back": "メキシコ",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "切ります",
      "reading": "To cut, slice",
      "back": "切[き]ります",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "送ります",
      "reading": "To send",
      "back": "送[おく]ります",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "あげます",
      "reading": "To give",
      "back": "あげます",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "もらいます",
      "reading": "To receive",
      "back": "もらいます",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "貸します",
      "reading": "To lend",
      "back": "貸[か]します",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "借ります",
      "reading": "To borrow",
      "back": "借[か]ります",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "教えます",
      "reading": "To teach",
      "back": "教[おし]えます",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "習います",
      "reading": "To learn",
      "back": "習[なら]います",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "かけます［電話を～］",
      "reading": "make [a phone call]",
      "back": "かけます［ 電話[でんわ]を~］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "手",
      "reading": "hand, arm",
      "back": "手[て]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "はし",
      "reading": "chopsticks",
      "back": "はし",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "スプーン",
      "reading": "spoon",
      "back": "スプーン",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "ナイフ",
      "reading": "knife",
      "back": "ナイフ",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "フォーク",
      "reading": "fork",
      "back": "フォーク",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "はさみ",
      "reading": "scissors",
      "back": "はさみ",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "パソコン",
      "reading": "personal computer",
      "back": "パソコン",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "ケータイ （でんわ）",
      "reading": "mobile phone, cell phone",
      "back": "ケータイ（でんわ）",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "メール",
      "reading": "e-mail",
      "back": "メール",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "年賀状",
      "reading": "New Year's greeting card",
      "back": "年賀状[ねんがじょう]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "パンチ",
      "reading": "punch",
      "back": "パンチ",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "ホッチキス",
      "reading": "stapler",
      "back": "ホッチキス",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "セロテープ",
      "reading": "Sellotape, Scotch tap, clear adhesive tap",
      "back": "セロテープ",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "消しゴム",
      "reading": "rubber, eraser",
      "back": "消しゴム[けしごむ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "紙",
      "reading": "paper",
      "back": "紙[かみ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "花",
      "reading": "flower, blossom",
      "back": "花[はな]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "シャツ",
      "reading": "shirt",
      "back": "シャツ",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "プレゼント",
      "reading": "present, gift",
      "back": "プレゼント",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "荷物",
      "reading": "luggage, baggage, parcel",
      "back": "荷物[にもつ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "お金",
      "reading": "money",
      "back": "お 金[かね]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "きっぷ",
      "reading": "ticket",
      "back": "きっぷ",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "クリスマス",
      "reading": "Christmas",
      "back": "クリスマス",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "父",
      "reading": "(my) father",
      "back": "父[ちち]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "母",
      "reading": "(my) mother",
      "back": "母[はは]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "お父さん",
      "reading": "(someone else's) father (also used to address one's own father)",
      "back": "お 父[とう]さん",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "お母さん",
      "reading": "(someone else's) mother (also used to address one's own mother)",
      "back": "お 母[かあ]さん",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "もう",
      "reading": "already",
      "back": "もう",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "まだ",
      "reading": "not yet",
      "back": "まだ",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "これから",
      "reading": "from now on, soon",
      "back": "これから",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "［～、］すてきですね。",
      "reading": "What a nice [~]!",
      "back": "［~、］すてきですね。",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "いらっしゃい。",
      "reading": "How nice of you to come. (lit. Welcome.)",
      "back": "いらっしゃい。",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "どうぞ　お上がり　ください",
      "reading": "Do come in.",
      "back": "どうぞ　お 上[あ]がり　ください",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "失礼します。",
      "reading": "May I? (lit. I commit an incivility.)",
      "back": "失礼[しつれい]します。",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "［～は］いかがですか。",
      "reading": "Won't you have [~]?/Would you like to have [~]? (used when offering something)",
      "back": "［~は］いかがですか。",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "いただきます",
      "reading": "Thank you./I accept. (said before starting to eat or drink)",
      "back": "いただきます",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "ごちそうさま［でした］。",
      "reading": "That was delicious. (said after eating or drinking)",
      "back": "ごちそうさま［でした］。",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "スパイン",
      "reading": "Spain",
      "back": "スパイン",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "ハンサム［な］",
      "reading": "handsome",
      "back": "ハンサム［な］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "きれい［な］",
      "reading": "beautiful, clean",
      "back": "きれい［な］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "静かに［な］",
      "reading": "quiet",
      "back": "静[しず]かに［な］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "にぎやか［な］",
      "reading": "lively",
      "back": "にぎやか［な］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "有名［な］",
      "reading": "famous",
      "back": "有名[ゆうめい]［な］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "親切［な］",
      "reading": "helpful, kind, considerate (not used about one's own family members)",
      "back": "親切[しんせつ]［な］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "元気［な］",
      "reading": "healthy, energetic, cheerful",
      "back": "元気[げんき]［な］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "暇［な］",
      "reading": "free (time)",
      "back": "暇[ひま]［な］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "便利［な］",
      "reading": "convenient",
      "back": "便利[べんり]［な］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "すてき［な］",
      "reading": "fine, nice, wonderful",
      "back": "すてき［な］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "大きく［な］",
      "reading": "big, large",
      "back": "大[おお]きく［な］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "小さい",
      "reading": "small, little",
      "back": "小[ちい]さい",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "新しい",
      "reading": "new, fresh",
      "back": "新[あたら]しい",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "古い",
      "reading": "old (not used to describe a person's age)",
      "back": "古[ふる]い",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "いい　（よい）",
      "reading": "good",
      "back": "いい　（よい）",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "悪い",
      "reading": "bad",
      "back": "悪[わる]い",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "暑い、熱い",
      "reading": "hot",
      "back": "暑[あつ]い、 熱[あつ]い",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "寒い",
      "reading": "cold (referring to temperature)",
      "back": "寒[さむ]い",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "冷たい",
      "reading": "cold (referring to touch)",
      "back": "冷[つめ]たい",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "難しい",
      "reading": "difficult",
      "back": "難[むずか]しい",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "易しい",
      "reading": "easy, tender, kind, gentle, graceful, affectionate, amiable&nbsp;",
      "back": "易[やさ]しい",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "高い",
      "reading": "expensive, tall, high",
      "back": "高[たか]い",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "安い",
      "reading": "inexpensive, cheap",
      "back": "安[やす]い",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "低い",
      "reading": "low",
      "back": "低[ひく]い",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "おもしろい",
      "reading": "interesting",
      "back": "おもしろい",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "おいしい",
      "reading": "delicious",
      "back": "おいしい",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "忙しい",
      "reading": "busy",
      "back": "忙[いそが]しい",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "楽しい",
      "reading": "enjoyable",
      "back": "楽[たの]しい",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "白い",
      "reading": "white",
      "back": "白[しろ]い",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "黒い",
      "reading": "black",
      "back": "黒[くろ]い",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "赤い",
      "reading": "red",
      "back": "赤[あか]い",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "青い",
      "reading": "blue",
      "back": "青[あお]い",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "桜",
      "reading": "cherry (blossom)",
      "back": "桜[さくら]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "山",
      "reading": "mountain",
      "back": "山[やま]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "町",
      "reading": "town, city",
      "back": "町[まち]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "食べ物",
      "reading": "food",
      "back": "食べ物[たべもの]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "所",
      "reading": "place",
      "back": "所[ところ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "寮",
      "reading": "dormitory",
      "back": "寮[りょう]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "レストラン",
      "reading": "restaurant",
      "back": "レストラン",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "生活",
      "reading": "Everyday life",
      "back": "生活[せいかつ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "［お］仕事",
      "reading": "work, business (～を　します：do one's job, work)",
      "back": "［お］ 仕事[しごと]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "どう",
      "reading": "how",
      "back": "どう",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "どんな～",
      "reading": "what kind of ~",
      "back": "どんな~",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "とても",
      "reading": "very",
      "back": "とても",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "あまり",
      "reading": "not so (used with negatives)",
      "back": "あまり&nbsp;",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "そして",
      "reading": "and (used to connect sentences)",
      "back": "そして",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "～が、～",
      "reading": "~, but ~",
      "back": "~が、~",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "おげんきですか。",
      "reading": "How are you?",
      "back": "おげんきですか。",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "［〜、］もう　一杯　いかがですか。",
      "reading": "Won't you have another cup of [~]?",
      "back": "［〜、］もう　一杯[いっぱい]　いかがですか。",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "［いいえ、］けっこうです。",
      "reading": "No, thank you.",
      "back": "［いいえ、］けっこうです。",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "もう　～です［ね］。",
      "reading": "It's already ~ [,isn't it?]",
      "back": "もう　~です［ね］。",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "そろそろ　失礼します。",
      "reading": "It's time I was going.",
      "back": "そろそろ　 失礼[しつれい]します。",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "いいえ。",
      "reading": "Not at all.",
      "back": "いいえ。",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "また　いらっしゃって　ください。",
      "reading": "Please come again.",
      "back": "また　いらっしゃって　ください。",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "シャンハイ　上海",
      "reading": "Shanghai",
      "back": "シャンハイ　 上海[しゃんはい]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "金閣寺",
      "reading": "Kinkakuji Temple (the Golden Pavilion)",
      "back": "金閣寺[きんかくじ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "なら　こえん",
      "reading": "Nara Park",
      "back": "なら　こえん",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "富士山",
      "reading": "Mt. Fuji",
      "back": "富士山[ふじさん]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "わかります",
      "reading": "To understand",
      "back": "わかります",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "好き［な］",
      "reading": "like",
      "back": "好[す]き［な］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "嫌い［な］",
      "reading": "dislike",
      "back": "嫌[きら]い［な］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "上手です［な］",
      "reading": "good at",
      "back": "上手[じょうず]です［な］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "下手［な］",
      "reading": "poor at",
      "back": "下手[へた]［な］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "飲み物",
      "reading": "drinks",
      "back": "飲み物[のみもの]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "りょうり",
      "reading": "dish (cooked food), cooking (～を　します：to cook)",
      "back": "りょうり",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "スポーツ",
      "reading": "sport (～を　します：play sports)",
      "back": "スポーツ",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "野球",
      "reading": "baseball (～を　します：to play baseball)",
      "back": "野球[やきゅう]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "ダンス",
      "reading": "Dance (～を　します：to dance)",
      "back": "ダンス",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "旅行",
      "reading": "trip, tour (～［を］　します：to travel, make a trip)",
      "back": "旅行[りょこう]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "音楽",
      "reading": "music",
      "back": "音楽[おんがく]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "歌",
      "reading": "song",
      "back": "歌[うた]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "クラシック",
      "reading": "classical music",
      "back": "クラシック",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "ジャズ",
      "reading": "jazz",
      "back": "ジャズ",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "コンサート",
      "reading": "concert",
      "back": "コンサート",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "カラオケ",
      "reading": "karaoke",
      "back": "カラオケ",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "歌舞伎",
      "reading": "Kabuki (traditional Japanese musical drama)",
      "back": "歌舞伎[かぶき]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "絵",
      "reading": "picture, drawing",
      "back": "絵[え]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "字",
      "reading": "letter, character",
      "back": "字[じ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "漢字",
      "reading": "Chinese character",
      "back": "漢字[かんじ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "ひらがな",
      "reading": "hiragana script",
      "back": "ひらがな",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "かたかな",
      "reading": "katakana script",
      "back": "かたかな",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "ローマ字",
      "reading": "the Roman alphabet",
      "back": "ローマ字[ろーまじ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "細かい　お金",
      "reading": "small change",
      "back": "細[こま]かい　お 金[かね]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "時間",
      "reading": "time",
      "back": "時間[じかん]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "用事",
      "reading": "something to do, errand",
      "back": "用事[ようじ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "約束",
      "reading": "appointment, promise (～［を］　します：to promise)",
      "back": "約束[やくそく]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "アルバイト",
      "reading": "side job (～を　します：to work part-time)",
      "back": "アルバイト",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "ご主人",
      "reading": "(someone else's) husband",
      "back": "ご 主人[しゅじん]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "夫／主人",
      "reading": "(my) husband",
      "back": "夫[おっと]／ 主人[しゅじん]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "奥さん",
      "reading": "(someone else's) wife",
      "back": "奥[おく]さん",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "妻／家内",
      "reading": "(my) wife",
      "back": "妻[つま]／ 家内[かない]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "子ども",
      "reading": "child",
      "back": "子[こ]ども",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "だいたい",
      "reading": "mostly, roughly",
      "back": "だいたい",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "たくさん",
      "reading": "many, much",
      "back": "たくさん",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "少し",
      "reading": "a little, a few",
      "back": "少[すこ]し",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "ぜんぜん",
      "reading": "not at all (used with negatives)",
      "back": "ぜんぜん",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "早く、速く",
      "reading": "early, quickly, fast",
      "back": "早[はや]く、 速[はや]く",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "どうして",
      "reading": "why",
      "back": "どうして",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "貸して　ください。",
      "reading": "Please lend (it to me).",
      "back": "貸[か]して　ください。",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "いいですよ。",
      "reading": "Sure./Certainly.",
      "back": "いいですよ。",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "ざんねんです［が］",
      "reading": "I'm sorry [,but], unfortunately",
      "back": "ざんねんです［が］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "ああ",
      "reading": "oh",
      "back": "ああ",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "いっしょに　いかがですか。",
      "reading": "Won't you join me (us)?",
      "back": "いっしょに　いかがですか。",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "［～は］　ちょっと",
      "reading": "[~] is a bit difficult. (a euphemism used when declining an invitation)",
      "back": "［~は］　ちょっと",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "だめですか。",
      "reading": "So you can't (come)?",
      "back": "だめですか。",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "また　今度　お願いします。",
      "reading": "Please ask me again some other time. (used when refusing an invitation indirectly, considering someone's feelings)",
      "back": "また　 今度[こんど]　お 願[ねが]いします。",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "あります",
      "reading": "to exist, be (referring to inanimate things)",
      "back": "あります",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "います",
      "reading": "to exist, be (referring to animate things)",
      "back": "います",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "いろいろ［な］",
      "reading": "various",
      "back": "いろいろ［な］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "男の　人",
      "reading": "man",
      "back": "男[おとこ]の　 人[ひと]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "女の 人",
      "reading": "woman",
      "back": "女[おんな]の 人[ひと]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "男の　子",
      "reading": "boy",
      "back": "男[おとこ]の　 子[こ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "女の　子",
      "reading": "girl",
      "back": "女[おんな]の　 子[こ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "犬",
      "reading": "dog",
      "back": "犬[いぬ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "猫",
      "reading": "cat",
      "back": "猫[ねこ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "パンダ",
      "reading": "panda",
      "back": "パンダ",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "象",
      "reading": "elephant",
      "back": "象[ぞう]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "木",
      "reading": "tree, wood",
      "back": "木[き]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "物",
      "reading": "thing",
      "back": "物[もの]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "電池",
      "reading": "battery",
      "back": "電池[でんち]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "箱",
      "reading": "box",
      "back": "箱[はこ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "スイッチ",
      "reading": "switch",
      "back": "スイッチ",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "冷蔵庫",
      "reading": "refrigerator",
      "back": "冷蔵庫[れいぞうこ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "テーブル",
      "reading": "table",
      "back": "テーブル",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "ベッド",
      "reading": "bed",
      "back": "ベッド",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "棚",
      "reading": "shelf",
      "back": "棚[たな]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "ドア",
      "reading": "door",
      "back": "ドア",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "窓",
      "reading": "window",
      "back": "窓[まど]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "ポスト",
      "reading": "postbox, mailbox",
      "back": "ポスト",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "ビル",
      "reading": "building",
      "back": "ビル&nbsp;",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "ATM",
      "reading": "cash machine, ATM (Automatic Teller Machine)",
      "back": "ATM",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "コンビニ",
      "reading": "convenience store",
      "back": "コンビニ",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "公園",
      "reading": "park",
      "back": "公園[こうえん]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "喫茶店",
      "reading": "cafe, coffee shop",
      "back": "喫茶店[きっさてん]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "～屋",
      "reading": "~ shop, ~ store",
      "back": "~ 屋[や]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "乗り場",
      "reading": "a fixed place to catch taxis, trains, etc.",
      "back": "乗り場[のりば]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "県",
      "reading": "prefecture",
      "back": "県[けん]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "上",
      "reading": "on, above, over",
      "back": "上[うえ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "下",
      "reading": "under, below, beneath",
      "back": "下[した]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "前",
      "reading": "front, before",
      "back": "前[まえ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "うしろ",
      "reading": "back, behind",
      "back": "うしろ",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "右",
      "reading": "right [side]",
      "back": "右[みぎ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "左",
      "reading": "left [side]",
      "back": "左[ひだり]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "中",
      "reading": "in, inside",
      "back": "中[なか]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "外",
      "reading": "outside",
      "back": "外[そと]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "隣",
      "reading": "next, next door",
      "back": "隣[となり]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "近く",
      "reading": "near, vicinity",
      "back": "近[ちか]く",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "間",
      "reading": "between, among",
      "back": "間[あいだ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "～や　～［など］",
      "reading": "~, ~, and so on",
      "back": "~や　~［など］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "［どうも］　すみません。",
      "reading": "Thank you.",
      "back": "［どうも］　すみません。",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "ナンプラー",
      "reading": "nam pla (fish sauce)",
      "back": "ナンプラー",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "コーナー",
      "reading": "corner, section",
      "back": "コーナー",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "いちばん　下",
      "reading": "the bottom",
      "back": "いちばん　 下[した]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "とうきょう　デズニーランド",
      "reading": "Tokyo Disneyland",
      "back": "とうきょう　デズニーランド",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "います　［子どもが〜］",
      "reading": "to have [a child]",
      "back": "います　［ 子[こ]どもが〜］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "います［日本に～］",
      "reading": "to stay, be [in Japan]",
      "back": "います［ 日本[にっほん]に~］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "かかります",
      "reading": "to take, cost (referring to time or money)",
      "back": "かかります",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "休みます　［会社を～］",
      "reading": "to take a day off [work]",
      "back": "休[やす]みます　［ 会社[かいしゃ]を~］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "一つ",
      "reading": "one (used when counting things)",
      "back": "一[ひと]つ",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "二つ",
      "reading": "two (things)",
      "back": "二[ふた]つ",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "三つ",
      "reading": "three (things)",
      "back": "三[みっ]つ",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "四つ",
      "reading": "four (things)",
      "back": "四[よっ]つ",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "五つ",
      "reading": "five (things)",
      "back": "五[いつ]つ",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "六つ",
      "reading": "six (things)",
      "back": "六[むっ]つ",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "七つ",
      "reading": "seven (things)",
      "back": "七[なな]つ",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "八つ",
      "reading": "eight things",
      "back": "八[やっ]つ",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "九つ",
      "reading": "nine (things)",
      "back": "九[ここの]つ",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "とう",
      "reading": "ten (things)",
      "back": "とう",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "いくつ",
      "reading": "how many (things)",
      "back": "いくつ",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "一人",
      "reading": "one person",
      "back": "一人[ひとり]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "二人",
      "reading": "two people",
      "back": "二人[ふたり]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "ー人",
      "reading": "- people",
      "back": "ー人[にん]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "－台",
      "reading": "counter for machines, cars, etc.",
      "back": "ー台[だい]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "－枚",
      "reading": "counter for paper, stamps, etc.",
      "back": "ー枚[まい]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "－回",
      "reading": "- times",
      "back": "ー回[かい]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "りんご",
      "reading": "apple",
      "back": "りんご",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "みかん",
      "reading": "mandarin orange",
      "back": "みかん",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "サンドイッチ",
      "reading": "sandwich",
      "back": "サンドイッチ",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "かれー［ライス］",
      "reading": "curry [with rice]",
      "back": "かれー［ライス］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "アイスクリーム",
      "reading": "ice cream",
      "back": "アイスクリーム",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "切手",
      "reading": "postage stamp",
      "back": "切手[きって]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "はがき",
      "reading": "postcard",
      "back": "はがき",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "封筒",
      "reading": "envelope",
      "back": "封筒[ふうとう]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "両親",
      "reading": "parents",
      "back": "両親[りょうしん]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "兄弟",
      "reading": "brothers and sisters, siblings",
      "back": "兄弟[きょうだい]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "兄",
      "reading": "(my) elder brother",
      "back": "兄[あに]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "お兄さん",
      "reading": "(someone else's) elder brother",
      "back": "お 兄[にい]さん",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "姉",
      "reading": "(my) elder sister",
      "back": "姉[あね]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "お姉さん",
      "reading": "(someone else's) elder sister",
      "back": "お 姉[ねえ]さん",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "弟",
      "reading": "(my) younger brother",
      "back": "弟[おとうと]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "弟さん",
      "reading": "(someone else's) younger brother",
      "back": "弟[おとうと]さん",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "妹",
      "reading": "(my) younger sister",
      "back": "妹[いもうと]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "妹さん",
      "reading": "(someone else's) younger sister",
      "back": "妹[いもうと]さん",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "外国",
      "reading": "foreign country",
      "back": "外国[がいこく]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "りゅうがくせい",
      "reading": "foreign student",
      "back": "りゅうがくせい",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "クラス",
      "reading": "class",
      "back": "クラス",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "－時間",
      "reading": "- hours(s)",
      "back": "ー時間[じかん]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "ーしゅうかん",
      "reading": "- week(s)",
      "back": "ーしゅうかん",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "ーか月",
      "reading": "- month(s)",
      "back": "ーか 月[げつ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "－年",
      "reading": "- year(s)",
      "back": "ー年[ねん]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "～ぐらい　",
      "reading": "about ~",
      "back": "~ぐらい",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "どのくらい",
      "reading": "how long",
      "back": "どのくらい",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "全部で",
      "reading": "in total",
      "back": "全部[ぜんぶ]で",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "みんな",
      "reading": "all, everything, everyone",
      "back": "みんな",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "ーだけ",
      "reading": "only ~",
      "back": "ーだけ",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "かしこまりました。",
      "reading": "Certainly, (Sir/Madam).",
      "back": "かしこまりました。",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "いい　［お］天気ですね。",
      "reading": "Nice weather, isn't it?",
      "back": "いい　［お］ 天気[てんき]ですね。",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "お出かけですか。",
      "reading": "Are you going out?",
      "back": "お 出[で]かけですか。",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "ちょっと　～まで。",
      "reading": "I'm just going to ~.",
      "back": "ちょっと　~まで。",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "行ってらっしゃい。",
      "reading": "See you later./So long. (lit. Go and come back.)",
      "back": "行[い]ってらっしゃい。",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "行って　きます。",
      "reading": "See you later./So long. (lit. I'm going and coming back.)",
      "back": "行[い]って　きます。",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "船便",
      "reading": "sea mail",
      "back": "船便[ふなびん]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "航空便　（エアマール）",
      "reading": "airmail",
      "back": "航空[こうくう] 便[びん]　（エアマール）",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "お願いします。",
      "reading": "Please. (lit. ask for a favor)",
      "back": "お 願[ねが]いします。",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "オーストラリア",
      "reading": "Australia",
      "back": "オーストラリア",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "簡単［な］",
      "reading": "easy, simple",
      "back": "簡単[かんたん]［な］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "近い",
      "reading": "near",
      "back": "近[ちか]い",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "遠い",
      "reading": "far",
      "back": "遠[とお]い",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "早い、速い",
      "reading": "fast, early",
      "back": "早[はや]い、 速[はや]い",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "遅い",
      "reading": "slow, late",
      "back": "遅[おそ]い",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "多い　［人が～］",
      "reading": "many [people], much",
      "back": "多[おお]い　［ 人[ひと]が~］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "少ない［人が～］",
      "reading": "few [people], a little",
      "back": "少[すく]ない［ 人[ひと]が~］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "暖かい、温かい",
      "reading": "warm",
      "back": "暖[あたた]かい、 温[あたた]かい",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "涼しい",
      "reading": "cool",
      "back": "涼[すず]しい",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "甘い",
      "reading": "sweet",
      "back": "甘[あま]い",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "辛い",
      "reading": "hot (taste), spicy",
      "back": "辛[から]い",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "重い",
      "reading": "heavy",
      "back": "重[おも]い",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "軽い",
      "reading": "light",
      "back": "軽[かる]い",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "いい［コーヒーが～］",
      "reading": "prefer [coffee]",
      "back": "いい［コーヒーが~］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "季節",
      "reading": "season",
      "back": "季節[きせつ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "春",
      "reading": "spring",
      "back": "春[はる]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "夏",
      "reading": "summer",
      "back": "夏[なつ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "秋",
      "reading": "autumn, fall",
      "back": "秋[あき]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "冬",
      "reading": "winter",
      "back": "冬[ふゆ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "天気",
      "reading": "weather",
      "back": "天気[てんき]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "雨",
      "reading": "rain, rainy",
      "back": "雨[あめ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "雪",
      "reading": "snow, snowy",
      "back": "雪[ゆき]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "曇り",
      "reading": "cloudy",
      "back": "曇[くも]り",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "ホテル",
      "reading": "hotel",
      "back": "ホテル",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "空港",
      "reading": "airport",
      "back": "空港[くうこう]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "海",
      "reading": "sea, ocean",
      "back": "海[うみ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "世界",
      "reading": "world",
      "back": "世界[せかい]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "パーティー",
      "reading": "party (～を　します：to give a party)",
      "back": "パーティー",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "［お］祭り",
      "reading": "festival",
      "back": "［お］ 祭[まつ]り",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "すき焼き",
      "reading": "sukiyaki (beef and vegetable hot pot)",
      "back": "すき 焼[や]き",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "刺身",
      "reading": "sashimi (sliced raw fish)",
      "back": "刺身[さしみ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "［お］すし",
      "reading": "sushi (vinegared rice topped with raw rish)",
      "back": "［お］すし",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "てんぷら",
      "reading": "tempura (seafood and vegetables deep fried in batter)",
      "back": "てんぷら",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "豚肉",
      "reading": "pork",
      "back": "豚肉[ぶたにく]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "鶏肉",
      "reading": "chicken",
      "back": "鶏肉[けいにく]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "牛肉",
      "reading": "beef",
      "back": "牛肉[ぎゅうにく]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "レモン",
      "reading": "lemon",
      "back": "レモン",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "生け花",
      "reading": "flower arrangement (～を　します：to practice flower arrangement)",
      "back": "生け花[いけばな]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "紅葉",
      "reading": "maple, red leaves of autumn",
      "back": "紅葉[もみじ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "どちらも",
      "reading": "both",
      "back": "どちらも",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "いちばん",
      "reading": "the most",
      "back": "いちばん",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "ずっと",
      "reading": "by far",
      "back": "ずっと",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "初めて",
      "reading": "for the first time",
      "back": "初[はじ]めて",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "ただいま。",
      "reading": "I'm home.",
      "back": "ただいま。",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "お帰りなさい。",
      "reading": "Welcome home.",
      "back": "お 帰[かえ]りなさい。",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "わあ、すごい　ひとですね。",
      "reading": "Wow! Look at all those people!",
      "back": "わあ、すごい　ひとですね。",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "疲れました。",
      "reading": "I'm tired",
      "back": "疲[つか]れました。",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "祇園祭",
      "reading": "the Gion Festival (the most famous festival in Kyoto)",
      "back": "祇園祭[ぎおんまつり]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "<div>ホンコン　（香港）</div>",
      "reading": "Hong Kong",
      "back": "ホンコン　（ 香港[ほんこん]）",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "シンガポール",
      "reading": "Singapore",
      "back": "シンガポール",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "遊びます",
      "reading": "to enjoy oneself, play",
      "back": "遊[あそ]びます",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "泳ぎます",
      "reading": "to swim",
      "back": "泳[およ]ぎます",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "迎えます",
      "reading": "to go to meet, welcome",
      "back": "迎[むか]えます",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "つかれます",
      "reading": "to get tired (when expressing the condition of being tired, つかれました is used)",
      "back": "つかれます",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "結婚します",
      "reading": "to marry, get married",
      "back": "結婚[けっこん]します",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "買い物します",
      "reading": "to do shopping",
      "back": "買い物[かいもの]します",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "食事します",
      "reading": "to have a meal, dine",
      "back": "食事[しょくじ]します",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "散歩します　［公園を～］",
      "reading": "to take a walk [in a park]",
      "back": "散歩[さんぽ]します　［ 公園[こうえん]を~］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "大変［な］",
      "reading": "hard, tough, severe, awful",
      "back": "大変[たいへん]［な］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "欲しい",
      "reading": "want (something)",
      "back": "欲[ほ]しい",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "広い",
      "reading": "wide, spacious",
      "back": "広[ひろ]い",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "狭い",
      "reading": "narrow, small (room, etc.)",
      "back": "狭[せま]い",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "プール",
      "reading": "swimming pool",
      "back": "プール",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "川",
      "reading": "river",
      "back": "川[かわ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "美術",
      "reading": "fine arts",
      "back": "美術[びじゅつ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "釣り",
      "reading": "fishing (～を　します：to fish, anble)",
      "back": "釣[つ]り",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "スキー",
      "reading": "skiing (～を　します：to ski)",
      "back": "スキー",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "週末",
      "reading": "weekend",
      "back": "週末[しゅうまつ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "［お］正月",
      "reading": "New Year's Day",
      "back": "［お］ 正月[しょうがつ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "～ごろ",
      "reading": "about ~ (time)",
      "back": "~ごろ",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "何か",
      "reading": "something",
      "back": "何[なに]か",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "どこか",
      "reading": "somewhere, some place",
      "back": "どこか",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "のどが　かわきます",
      "reading": "to get thirsty (when expressing the condition of being thirsty, のどが　かわきました　is used)",
      "back": "のどが　かわきます",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "おなかが　すきます",
      "reading": "to get hungry (when expressing the condition of being hungry, おなかが　すきました　is used)",
      "back": "おなかが　すきます",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "そう　しましょう。",
      "reading": "Let's do that. (used when agreeing with someone's suggestion)",
      "back": "そう　しましょう。",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "ご　注　もんは？",
      "reading": "May I take your order?",
      "back": "ご　 注[ちゅう]　もんは？",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "定食",
      "reading": "set meal, table d'hote",
      "back": "定食[ていしょく]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "牛どん",
      "reading": "bowl of rice topped with beef",
      "back": "牛[ぎゅう]どん",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "［少々］お待ちください",
      "reading": "Please wait [a moment]. (polite equivalent of です)",
      "back": "［ 少々[しょうしょう]］お 待[ま]ちください",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "別々に",
      "reading": "separately",
      "back": "別々[べつべつ]に",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "つけます&nbsp;",
      "reading": "to turn on",
      "back": "つけます",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "消します",
      "reading": "to turn off",
      "back": "消[け]します",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "開けます",
      "reading": "to open",
      "back": "開[あ]けます",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "閉めます",
      "reading": "to close, shut",
      "back": "閉[し]めます",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "急ぎます",
      "reading": "to hurry",
      "back": "急[いそ]ぎます",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "待ちます",
      "reading": "to wait",
      "back": "待[ま]ちます",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "持ちます",
      "reading": "to hold",
      "back": "持[も]ちます",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "取ります",
      "reading": "to take, pass",
      "back": "取[と]ります",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "手伝います",
      "reading": "To help (with a task)",
      "back": "手伝[てつだ]います",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "呼びます",
      "reading": "To call",
      "back": "呼[よ]びます",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "話します",
      "reading": "to speak, talk",
      "back": "話[はな]します",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "使います",
      "reading": "To use",
      "back": "使[つか]います",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "止めます",
      "reading": "to stop, park",
      "back": "止[と]めます",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "見せます",
      "reading": "to show",
      "back": "見[み]せます",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "教えます　［住所を～］",
      "reading": "to tell [an address]",
      "back": "教[おし]えます　［ 住所[じゅうしょ]を~］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "座ります",
      "reading": "to sit down",
      "back": "座[すわ]ります",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "立ちます",
      "reading": "To stand up",
      "back": "立[た]ちます",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "入ります　［喫茶店に～］",
      "reading": "to enter [a cafe]",
      "back": "入[はい]ります　［ 喫茶店[きっさてん]に~］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "出ます［喫茶店を～］",
      "reading": "to go out [of a cafe]",
      "back": "出[で]ます［ 喫茶店[きっさてん]を~］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "降ります［雨が～］",
      "reading": "to rain",
      "back": "降[ふり]ります［ 雨[あめ]が~］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "コピーします",
      "reading": "to copy",
      "back": "コピーします",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "電気",
      "reading": "electricity, light",
      "back": "電気[でんき]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "エアコン",
      "reading": "air conditioner",
      "back": "エアコン",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "パスポート",
      "reading": "passport",
      "back": "パスポート",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "名前",
      "reading": "name",
      "back": "名前[なまえ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "住所",
      "reading": "address",
      "back": "住所[じゅうしょ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "地図",
      "reading": "map",
      "back": "地図[ちず]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "塩",
      "reading": "salt",
      "back": "塩[しお]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "砂糖",
      "reading": "sugar",
      "back": "砂糖[さとう]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "問題",
      "reading": "question, problem, trouble",
      "back": "問題[もんだい]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "答え",
      "reading": "answer",
      "back": "答[こた]え",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "読み方",
      "reading": "how to read, way of reading",
      "back": "読み方[よみかた]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "～方",
      "reading": "how to ~, way of ~ing",
      "back": "~ 方[かた]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "まっすぐ",
      "reading": "straight",
      "back": "まっすぐ",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "ゆっくり",
      "reading": "slowly, leisurely",
      "back": "ゆっくり",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "すぐ",
      "reading": "immediately",
      "back": "すぐ",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "また",
      "reading": "again",
      "back": "また",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "あとで",
      "reading": "later",
      "back": "あとで",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "もう　少し",
      "reading": "a little more",
      "back": "もう　 少[すこ]し",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "もう　～",
      "reading": "~ more, another ~",
      "back": "もう　~",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "さあ",
      "reading": "right (used when encouraging some course of action)",
      "back": "さあ",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "あれ？",
      "reading": "Oh! Eh? (in surprise or wonder)",
      "back": "あれ？",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "信号を　右へ　曲がって　ください。",
      "reading": "Turn right at the traffic lights.",
      "back": "信号[しんごう]を　 右[みぎ]へ　 曲[ま]がって　ください。",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "これで　お願いします。",
      "reading": "I'd like to pay with this.",
      "back": "これで　お 願[ねが]いします。",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "お釣り",
      "reading": "change",
      "back": "お 釣[つ]り",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "置きます",
      "reading": "to put",
      "back": "置[お]きます",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "作ります、造ります",
      "reading": "to make, produce",
      "back": "作[つく]ります、 造[つく]ります",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "売ります",
      "reading": "to sell",
      "back": "売[う]ります",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "知ります",
      "reading": "to get to know",
      "back": "知[し]ります",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "済みます",
      "reading": "to live, dwell, reside, etc.&nbsp;",
      "back": "済[す]みます",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "研究します",
      "reading": "to do research",
      "back": "研究[けんきゅう]します",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "資料",
      "reading": "materials, data",
      "back": "資料[しりょう]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "カタログ",
      "reading": "catalogue",
      "back": "カタログ",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "時刻表",
      "reading": "timetable",
      "back": "時刻[じこく] 表[ひょう]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "服",
      "reading": "clothes",
      "back": "服[ふく]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "製品",
      "reading": "products",
      "back": "製品[せいひん]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "ソフト",
      "reading": "software",
      "back": "ソフト",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "電子辞書",
      "reading": "electric dictionary",
      "back": "電子[でんし] 辞書[じしょ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "経済",
      "reading": "economy",
      "back": "経済[けいざい]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "市役所",
      "reading": "municipal office, city hall",
      "back": "市役所[しやくしょ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "高校",
      "reading": "senior high school",
      "back": "高校[こうこう]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "歯医者",
      "reading": "dentist, dentist's",
      "back": "歯医者[はいしゃ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "独身",
      "reading": "single, unmarried",
      "back": "独身[どくしん]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "すみません",
      "reading": "I'm sorry.",
      "back": "すみません",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "みなさん",
      "reading": "Ladies and Gentlemen, everybody",
      "back": "みなさん",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "思い出します",
      "reading": "to remember, recollect",
      "back": "思い出[おもいだ]します",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "いらっしゃいます",
      "reading": "to be (honorific equivalent of います)",
      "back": "いらっしゃいます",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "乗ります　［電車に～］",
      "reading": "to ride, get on [a train]",
      "back": "乗[の]ります　［ 電車[でんしゃ]に~］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "降ります　［電車を～］",
      "reading": "to get off [a train]",
      "back": "降[お]ります　［ 電車[でんしゃ]を~］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "乗り換えます",
      "reading": "to change (train, etc.)",
      "back": "乗り換[のりか]えます",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "あびます　［シャワーを～］",
      "reading": "to take [a shower]",
      "back": "あびます　［シャワーを~］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "入れます",
      "reading": "to put in, insert",
      "back": "入[い]れます",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "出します",
      "reading": "to take out, hand in, send",
      "back": "出[だ]します",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "おろします　［お金を～］",
      "reading": "to withdraw",
      "back": "おろします　［お 金[かね]を~］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "入ります　［大学に～］",
      "reading": "to enter [university]",
      "back": "入[はい]ります　［ 大学[だいがく]に~］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "出ます　［大学を～］",
      "reading": "to graduate from [university]",
      "back": "出[で]ます　［ 大学[だいがく]を~］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "押します",
      "reading": "to push, press",
      "back": "押[お]します",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "始めます",
      "reading": "to start, begin",
      "back": "始[はじ]めます",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "見学します",
      "reading": "to tour, visit a place to study it",
      "back": "見学[けんがく]します",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "電話します",
      "reading": "to phone",
      "back": "電話[でんわ]します",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "若い",
      "reading": "young",
      "back": "若[わか]い",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "長い",
      "reading": "long",
      "back": "長[なが]い",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "短い",
      "reading": "short",
      "back": "短[みじか]い",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "明るい",
      "reading": "bright, light",
      "back": "明[あか]るい",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "暗い",
      "reading": "dark",
      "back": "暗[くら]い",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "体",
      "reading": "body, health",
      "back": "体[からだ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "頭",
      "reading": "head, brain",
      "back": "頭[あたま]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "髪",
      "reading": "hair",
      "back": "髪[かみ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "顔",
      "reading": "face",
      "back": "顔[かお]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "目",
      "reading": "eye",
      "back": "目[め]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "耳",
      "reading": "ear",
      "back": "耳[みみ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "鼻",
      "reading": "nose",
      "back": "鼻[はな]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "口",
      "reading": "mouth",
      "back": "口[くち]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "歯",
      "reading": "tooth",
      "back": "歯[は]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "おなか",
      "reading": "stomach",
      "back": "おなか",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "足",
      "reading": "leg, foot",
      "back": "足[あし]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "脊",
      "reading": "height",
      "back": "脊",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "サービス　",
      "reading": "service",
      "back": "サービス",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "ジョギング",
      "reading": "jogging (~を　します：to jog)",
      "back": "ジョギング",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "シャワー　",
      "reading": "shower",
      "back": "シャワー",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "緑",
      "reading": "green, greenery",
      "back": "緑[みどり]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "［お］寺",
      "reading": "Buddhist temple",
      "back": "［お］ 寺[てら]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "神社",
      "reading": "Shinto shrine",
      "back": "神社[じんじゃ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "－番",
      "reading": "number -&nbsp;",
      "back": "番[ばん]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "どうやって",
      "reading": "in what way, how",
      "back": "どうやって",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "どの～",
      "reading": "which ~ (used for three or more)",
      "back": "どの~",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "どれ",
      "reading": "which one (of three or more things)",
      "back": "どれ",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "すごいですね。",
      "reading": "That's amazing!",
      "back": "すごいですね。",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "［いいえ、］　まだまだです。",
      "reading": "[No,] I still have a long way to go.",
      "back": "［いいえ、］　まだまだです。",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "おひきだしですか。",
      "reading": "Are you making a withdrawal?",
      "back": "おひきだしですか。",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "まず",
      "reading": "first of all",
      "back": "まず",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "つぎに",
      "reading": "next, as a next step",
      "back": "つぎに",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "キャッシュカード",
      "reading": "cash dispensing card",
      "back": "キャッシュカード",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "安保番号",
      "reading": "personal identification number, PIN",
      "back": "安保[あんぽ] 番号[ばんごう]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "金額",
      "reading": "amount of money",
      "back": "金額[きんがく]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "確認",
      "reading": "confirmation (～します：to confirm)",
      "back": "確認[かくにん]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "ボタン",
      "reading": "button",
      "back": "ボタン",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "雪祭り",
      "reading": "Snow Festival",
      "back": "雪[ゆき] 祭[まつ]り",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "バンドン",
      "reading": "Bandung (in Indonesia)",
      "back": "バンドン",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "フランケン",
      "reading": "Franken (in Germany)",
      "back": "フランケン",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "ベラクルス",
      "reading": "Veracruz (in Mexico)",
      "back": "ベラクルス",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "覚えます",
      "reading": "to memorize",
      "back": "覚[おぼ]えます",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "忘れます",
      "reading": "to forget",
      "back": "忘[わす]れます",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "なくします",
      "reading": "to lose",
      "back": "なくします",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "払います",
      "reading": "to pay",
      "back": "払[はら]います",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "返します",
      "reading": "to give back, return",
      "back": "返[かえ]します",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "出かけます",
      "reading": "to go out",
      "back": "出[で]かけます",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "脱ぎます",
      "reading": "to take off (clothes, shoes, etc.)",
      "back": "脱[ぬ]ぎます",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "持って　行きます",
      "reading": "to take (something)",
      "back": "持[も]って　 行[い]きます",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "持って　来ます",
      "reading": "to bring (something)",
      "back": "持[も]って　 来[き]ます",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "心配します",
      "reading": "to worry",
      "back": "心配[しんぱい]します",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "残業します",
      "reading": "to work overtime",
      "back": "残業[ざんぎょう]します",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "出張します",
      "reading": "to go on a business trip",
      "back": "出張[しゅっちょう]します",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "飲みます　［薬を〜］",
      "reading": "to take [medicine] (literally to drink medicine)",
      "back": "飲[の]みます　［ 薬[くすり]を〜］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "入ります　［おふろに〜］",
      "reading": "to take [a bath]",
      "back": "入[はい]ります　［おふろに〜］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "大切［な］",
      "reading": "important, precious",
      "back": "大切[たいせつ]［な］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "大丈夫［な］",
      "reading": "all right",
      "back": "大丈夫[だいじょうぶ]［な］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "危ない",
      "reading": "dangerous",
      "back": "危[あぶ]ない",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "禁煙",
      "reading": "no smoking",
      "back": "禁煙[きんえん]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "［健康］　保険証",
      "reading": "[health] insurance card",
      "back": "［ 健康[けんこう]］　 保険[ほけん] 証[しょう]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "熱",
      "reading": "temperature, fever",
      "back": "熱[ねつ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "病気",
      "reading": "illness, disease",
      "back": "病気[びょうき]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "薬",
      "reading": "medicine",
      "back": "薬[くすり]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "［お］ふろ",
      "reading": "bath",
      "back": "［お］ふろ",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "上着",
      "reading": "jacket, outerwear",
      "back": "上着[うわぎ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "下着",
      "reading": "underwear",
      "back": "下着[したぎ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "２，３　日",
      "reading": "two or three days",
      "back": "２，３　 日[にち]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "２，３～",
      "reading": "two or three ~ (where ~ is a counter suffix)",
      "back": "２，３~",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "～までに",
      "reading": "before ~, by ~ (indicating time limit)",
      "back": "~までに",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "ですから",
      "reading": "therefore, so",
      "back": "ですから",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "どう　しましたか。",
      "reading": "What's the matter?",
      "back": "どう　しましたか。",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "のど",
      "reading": "throat",
      "back": "のど",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "［～が］　痛いです。",
      "reading": "(I) have a pain [in my ~].",
      "back": "［~が］　 痛[いた]いです。",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "かぜ",
      "reading": "cold, flu",
      "back": "かぜ",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "お大事に。",
      "reading": "Take care of yourself. (said to people who are ill)",
      "back": "お 大事[だいじ]に。",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "できます",
      "reading": "to be able to, can",
      "back": "できます",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "洗います",
      "reading": "to wash",
      "back": "洗[あら]います",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "弾きます",
      "reading": "<div>to play (stringed instrument, piano, etc.)<br></div>",
      "back": "弾[ひ]きます",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "歌います",
      "reading": "to sing",
      "back": "歌[うた]います",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "集めます",
      "reading": "to collect, gather",
      "back": "集[あつ]めます",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "捨てます",
      "reading": "to throw away",
      "back": "捨[す]てます",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "換えます",
      "reading": "to exchange, change",
      "back": "換[か]えます",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "運転します",
      "reading": "to drive",
      "back": "運転[うんてん]します",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "予約します",
      "reading": "to reserve, book",
      "back": "予約[よやく]します",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "ピアノ",
      "reading": "piano",
      "back": "ピアノ",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "メートル",
      "reading": "meter",
      "back": "メートル",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "現金",
      "reading": "cash",
      "back": "現金[げんきん]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "趣味",
      "reading": "hobby",
      "back": "趣味[しゅみ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "日記",
      "reading": "diary",
      "back": "日記[にっき]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "お祈り",
      "reading": "prayer (～を　します：to pray)",
      "back": "お 祈[いの]り",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "課長",
      "reading": "section head",
      "back": "課長[かちょう]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "部長",
      "reading": "department head",
      "back": "部長[ぶちょう]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "社長",
      "reading": "company president",
      "back": "社長[しゃちょう]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "動物",
      "reading": "animal",
      "back": "動物[どうぶつ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "馬",
      "reading": "horse",
      "back": "馬[うま]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "インターネット",
      "reading": "the Internet",
      "back": "インターネット",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "特に",
      "reading": "especially",
      "back": "特[とく]に",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "へえ",
      "reading": "What! Really! (used when expressing surprise)",
      "back": "へえ",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "それは　おもしろいですね。",
      "reading": "That's interesting, isn't it?",
      "back": "それは　おもしろいですね。",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "なかなか",
      "reading": "not easily (used with negatives)",
      "back": "なかなか",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "ほんとうですか。",
      "reading": "Really?",
      "back": "ほんとうですか。",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "ぜひ",
      "reading": "by all means, really",
      "back": "ぜひ",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "故郷",
      "reading": "Furusato (a song title meaning 'Home Town')",
      "back": "故郷[ふるさと]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "登ります、上ります",
      "reading": "to climb, go up",
      "back": "登[のぼ]ります、 上[のぼ]ります",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "泊まります［ホテルに～］　",
      "reading": "to stay [at a hotel]",
      "back": "泊[と]まります［ホテルに~］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "掃除します",
      "reading": "to clean (a room)",
      "back": "掃除[そうじ]します",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "洗濯します",
      "reading": "to wash (clothes)",
      "back": "洗濯[せんたく]します",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "なります",
      "reading": "to become",
      "back": "なります",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "眠い",
      "reading": "sleepy",
      "back": "眠[ねむ]い",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "強い",
      "reading": "strong",
      "back": "強[つよ]い",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "弱い",
      "reading": "weak",
      "back": "弱[よわ]い",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "練習",
      "reading": "practice (~[を] します: to practice)",
      "back": "練習[れんしゅう]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "ゴルフ",
      "reading": "golf (~を　します: to play golf)",
      "back": "ゴルフ",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "相撲",
      "reading": "sumo wrestling (～を　します: to wrestle)",
      "back": "相撲[すもう]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "日",
      "reading": "day, date",
      "back": "日[ひ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "調子",
      "reading": "condition",
      "back": "調子[ちょうし]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "一度",
      "reading": "once",
      "back": "一度[いちど]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "一度も",
      "reading": "not once, never (used with negatives)",
      "back": "一度[いちで]も",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "だんだん　",
      "reading": "gradually",
      "back": "だんだん",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "もうすぐ",
      "reading": "soon",
      "back": "もうすぐ",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "おかげさまで",
      "reading": "Thank you. (used when expressing gratitude for help received)",
      "back": "おかげさまで",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "でも",
      "reading": "but",
      "back": "でも",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "かんぱい",
      "reading": "Cheers!",
      "back": "かんぱい",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "ダイエット",
      "reading": "diet (～を　します: to go on a diet)",
      "back": "ダイエット",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "無理［な］",
      "reading": "excessive, impossible",
      "back": "無理[むり]［な］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "体に　いい",
      "reading": "good for one's health",
      "back": "体[からだ]に　いい",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "葛飾北斉　<b>(FIX)</b>",
      "reading": "a famous Edo-period woodblock artist and painter (1760-1849)",
      "back": "葛飾[かつしか] 北[きた] 斉[ひとし]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "要ります［ビザが～］",
      "reading": "to need, require [a visa]",
      "back": "要[い]ります［ビザが~］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "調べます",
      "reading": "to check, investigate",
      "back": "調[しら]べます",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "修理します",
      "reading": "to repair",
      "back": "修理[しゅうり]します",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "僕",
      "reading": "I (an informal equivalent of わたし used by men)",
      "back": "僕[ぼく]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "君",
      "reading": "you (an informal equivalent of あなた used to address people of equal or lower status)",
      "back": "君[きみ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "～君",
      "reading": "Mr. (an informal equivalent of ～さん used to address people of equal or lower status; also often appended to boys' names)",
      "back": "~ 君[くん]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "うん",
      "reading": "yes (an informal equivalent of はい)",
      "back": "うん",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "ううん",
      "reading": "no (an informal equivalent of いいえ)",
      "back": "ううん",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "ことば",
      "reading": "word, language",
      "back": "ことば",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "着物",
      "reading": "kimono (traditional Japanese attire)",
      "back": "着物[きもの]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "ビザ",
      "reading": "visa",
      "back": "ビザ",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "初め",
      "reading": "the beginning",
      "back": "初[はじ]め",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "終わり",
      "reading": "the end of ~, The End",
      "back": "終[お]わり",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "こっち",
      "reading": "this way, this place (an informal equivalent of こちら)",
      "back": "こっち",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "そっち",
      "reading": "that way, that place near the listener (an informal equivalent of そちら)",
      "back": "そっち",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "あっち",
      "reading": "that way, that place over there (an informal equivalent of あちら)",
      "back": "あっち",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "どっち",
      "reading": "which one (of two things), which way, where (an informal equivalent of どちら)",
      "back": "どっち",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "みんあで",
      "reading": "all together",
      "back": "みんあで",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "～けど",
      "reading": "~, but (an informal equivalent of が)",
      "back": "~けど",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "おなかが　いっぱいです",
      "reading": "(I'm) full",
      "back": "おなかが　いっぱいです",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "よかったら",
      "reading": "if you like",
      "back": "よかったら",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "思います",
      "reading": "to think",
      "back": "思[おも]います",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "言います",
      "reading": "to say",
      "back": "言[い]います",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "勝ちます",
      "reading": "to win",
      "back": "勝[か]ちます",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "負けます",
      "reading": "to lose, be beaten",
      "back": "負[ま]けます",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "あります　［おまつりが～］",
      "reading": "[a festival] to be held, take place",
      "back": "あります　［おまつりが~］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "役に　立ちます",
      "reading": "to be useful",
      "back": "役[やく]に　 立[た]ちます",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "動きます",
      "reading": "to move, work",
      "back": "動[うご]きます",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "やめます　［かいしゃを～］",
      "reading": "to quit or retire from work [a company], stop, give up",
      "back": "やめます　［かいしゃを~］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "気を　つけます",
      "reading": "to pay attention, take care",
      "back": "気[き]を　つけます",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "留学します",
      "reading": "to study abroad",
      "back": "留学[りゅうがく]します",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "むだ［な］",
      "reading": "wasteful",
      "back": "むだ［な］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "不便［な］",
      "reading": "inconvenient",
      "back": "不便[ふべん]［な］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "すごい",
      "reading": "awful, great (express astonishment or admiration)",
      "back": "すごい",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "ほんとう",
      "reading": "true",
      "back": "ほんとう",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "うそ",
      "reading": "lie",
      "back": "うそ",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "自動車",
      "reading": "car, automobile",
      "back": "自動車[じどうしゃ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "交通",
      "reading": "transport, traffic",
      "back": "交通[こうつう]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "物価",
      "reading": "[commodity] prices",
      "back": "物価[ぶっか]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "放送",
      "reading": "announcement, broadcast",
      "back": "放送[ほうそう]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "ニュース",
      "reading": "news",
      "back": "ニュース",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "アニメ",
      "reading": "anime (Japanese animation)",
      "back": "アニメ",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "マンガ",
      "reading": "comic book",
      "back": "マンガ",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "デザイン",
      "reading": "design, artwork",
      "back": "デザイン",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "夢",
      "reading": "dream",
      "back": "夢[ゆめ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "天才",
      "reading": "genius",
      "back": "天才[てんさい]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "試合",
      "reading": "game, match (～を　します: to play a game/match)",
      "back": "試合[しあい]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "意見",
      "reading": "opinion",
      "back": "意見[いけん]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "話",
      "reading": "talk, speech, what one says, story (～を　します: to talk, tell a story)",
      "back": "話[はなし]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "地球",
      "reading": "earth",
      "back": "地球[ちきゅう]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "月",
      "reading": "moon",
      "back": "月[つき]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "最近",
      "reading": "recently, these days",
      "back": "最近[さいきん]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "たぶん",
      "reading": "probably, perhaps, maybe",
      "back": "たぶん",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "きっと",
      "reading": "surely, definitely",
      "back": "きっと",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "ほんとうに",
      "reading": "really",
      "back": "ほんとうに",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "～に　ついて",
      "reading": "about ~, concerning ~",
      "back": "~に　ついて",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "久しぶりでしね。",
      "reading": "It's been a long time [since we last met].",
      "back": "久[ひさ]しぶりでしね。",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "～でも　飲みませんか。",
      "reading": "How about drinking ~ or something?",
      "back": "~でも　 飲[の]みませんか。",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "もちろん",
      "reading": "of course",
      "back": "もちろん",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "もう　帰らないと。。。",
      "reading": "I have to get home now...",
      "back": "もう　 帰[かえ]らないと。。。",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "着ます",
      "reading": "to put on (a shirt, etc.)",
      "back": "着[き]ます",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "はきます",
      "reading": "to put on (shoes, trousers, etc.)",
      "back": "はきます",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "かぶります",
      "reading": "to put on (a hat, etc.)",
      "back": "かぶります",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "かけます　［めがねを～］",
      "reading": "to put on [glasses]",
      "back": "かけます　［めがねを~］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "します　［ネクタイを～］",
      "reading": "to put on [a tie]",
      "back": "します　［ネクタイを~］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "生まれます",
      "reading": "to be born",
      "back": "生[う]まれます",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "わたしたち",
      "reading": "we",
      "back": "わたしたち",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "コート",
      "reading": "coat",
      "back": "コート",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "セーター",
      "reading": "sweater",
      "back": "セーター",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "スーツ",
      "reading": "suit",
      "back": "スーツ",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "帽子",
      "reading": "hat, cap",
      "back": "帽子[ぼうし]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "眼鏡",
      "reading": "glasses",
      "back": "眼鏡[めがね]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "ケーキ",
      "reading": "cake",
      "back": "ケーキ",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "［お］弁当",
      "reading": "box lunch",
      "back": "［お］ 弁当[べんとう]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "ロボット",
      "reading": "robot",
      "back": "ロボット",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "ユーモア",
      "reading": "humor",
      "back": "ユーモア",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "都合",
      "reading": "convenience",
      "back": "都合[つごう]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "よく",
      "reading": "often",
      "back": "よく",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "えーと",
      "reading": "well, let me see",
      "back": "えーと",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "おめでとう　［ございます］。",
      "reading": "Congratulations. (used on birthdays, at weddings, etc.)",
      "back": "おめでとう　［ございます］。",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "お探しですか。",
      "reading": "Are you looking for ~?",
      "back": "お 探[さが]しですか。",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "でわ",
      "reading": "well then,",
      "back": "でわ",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "家賃",
      "reading": "rent",
      "back": "家賃[やちん]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "ダイニングキッチン",
      "reading": "kitching with a dining area",
      "back": "ダイニングキッチン",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "和室",
      "reading": "Japanese-style room",
      "back": "和室[わしつ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "押入れ",
      "reading": "Japanese-style closet",
      "back": "押入[おしい]れ",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "布団",
      "reading": "Japanese-style mattress and quilt",
      "back": "布団[ふとん]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "聞きます［先生に～］",
      "reading": "to ask [the teacher]",
      "back": "聞[き]きます［ 先生[せんせい]に~］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "回します",
      "reading": "to turn",
      "back": "回[まわ]します",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "（障ります）［ドアに～］",
      "reading": "to touch [a door]",
      "back": "（ 障[さわ]ります）［ドアに~］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "出ます［お釣りが～］",
      "reading": "[change] to come out",
      "back": "出[で]ます［お 釣[つ]りが~］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "歩きます",
      "reading": "to walk",
      "back": "歩[ある]きます",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "渡ります［橋を～］",
      "reading": "to cross [a bridge]",
      "back": "渡[わた]ります［ 橋[はし]を~］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "曲がります［右へ～］",
      "reading": "to turn [to the right]",
      "back": "曲[ま]がります［ 右[みぎ]へ~］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "寂しい",
      "reading": "lonely",
      "back": "寂[さび]しい",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "［お］湯",
      "reading": "hot water",
      "back": "［お］ 湯[ゆ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "音",
      "reading": "sound",
      "back": "音[おと]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "サイズ",
      "reading": "size",
      "back": "サイズ",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "故障",
      "reading": "breakdown (～します: to break down)",
      "back": "故障[こしょう]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "道",
      "reading": "road, way",
      "back": "道[みち]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "交差点",
      "reading": "crossroads",
      "back": "交差点[こうさてん]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "信号",
      "reading": "traffic lights",
      "back": "信号[しんごう]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "角",
      "reading": "corner",
      "back": "角[かど]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "橋",
      "reading": "bridge",
      "back": "橋[はし]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "駐車場",
      "reading": "car park, parking lot",
      "back": "駐車[ちゅうしゃ] 場[じょう]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "なんかいも",
      "reading": "many times",
      "back": "なんかいも",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "～目",
      "reading": "the -th (indicating order)",
      "back": "~ 目[め]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "くれます",
      "reading": "to give (me)",
      "back": "くれます",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "直します",
      "reading": "to repair, correct",
      "back": "直[なお]します",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "連れて　行きます",
      "reading": "to take (someone)",
      "back": "連[つ]れて　 行[い]きます",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "連れて　来ます",
      "reading": "to bring (someone)",
      "back": "連[つ]れて　 来[き]ます",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "送ります［人を～］",
      "reading": "to escort [someone], go with",
      "back": "送[おく]ります［ 人[ひと]を~］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "紹介します",
      "reading": "to introduce",
      "back": "紹介[しょうかい]します",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "案内します",
      "reading": "to show around, show the way",
      "back": "案内[あんない]します",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "説明します",
      "reading": "to explain",
      "back": "説明[せつめい]します",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "おじいさん／おじちゃん",
      "reading": "grandfather, old man",
      "back": "おじいさん／おじちゃん",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "おばあさん／おばあちゃん",
      "reading": "grandmother, old woman",
      "back": "おばあさん／おばあちゃん",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "準備",
      "reading": "preparation (～［を］　します: to prepare)",
      "back": "準備[じゅんび]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "引っ越し",
      "reading": "moving out (～［を］　します: to move out)",
      "back": "引っ越[ひっこ]し",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "［お］菓子",
      "reading": "sweets, snacks",
      "back": "［お］ 菓子[かし]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "ホームステイ",
      "reading": "homestay",
      "back": "ホームステイ",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "全部",
      "reading": "all",
      "back": "全部[ぜんぶ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "自分で",
      "reading": "by oneself",
      "back": "自分[じぶん]で",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "ほかに",
      "reading": "besides",
      "back": "ほかに",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "考えます",
      "reading": "To think, consider",
      "back": "考[かんが]えます",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "着きます",
      "reading": "To arrive",
      "back": "着[つ]きます",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "取ります［年を～］",
      "reading": "To grow [old]",
      "back": "取[と]ります［ 年[とし]を~］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "足ります",
      "reading": "to be enough, be sufficient",
      "back": "足[た]ります",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "田舎",
      "reading": "countryside, hometown",
      "back": "田舎[いなか]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "チャンス",
      "reading": "chance",
      "back": "チャンス",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "億",
      "reading": "hundred million",
      "back": "億[おく]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "もし［～たら］",
      "reading": "if",
      "back": "もし［~たら］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "意味",
      "reading": "meaning",
      "back": "意味[いみ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "もしもし",
      "reading": "hello (used on the phone)",
      "back": "もしもし",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "転勤",
      "reading": "transfer (～します: to be transferred to another office)",
      "back": "転勤[てんきん]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "こと",
      "reading": "thing, matter (～の　こと: to thing about ~)",
      "back": "こと",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "暇",
      "reading": "free time",
      "back": "暇[ひま]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "［いろいろ］お世話に　なりました。",
      "reading": "Thank you for everything you've done for me.",
      "back": "［いろいろ］お 世話[せわ]に　なりました。",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "頑張ります",
      "reading": "do one's best",
      "back": "頑張[がんば]ります",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "どうぞ　お元気で。",
      "reading": "Please take care of yourself. (said when expecting a long separation)",
      "back": "どうぞ　お 元気[げんき]で。",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "ベトナム",
      "reading": "Vietnam",
      "back": "ベトナム",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "見ます（診ます）",
      "reading": "to check, take a look",
      "back": "見[み]ます（ 診[み]ます）",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "探します（捜します）",
      "reading": "to look for, search",
      "back": "探[さが]します（ 捜[さが]します）",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "遅れます［時間に〜］",
      "reading": "to be late [for an appointment, etc.]",
      "back": "遅[おく]れます［ 時間[じかん]に〜］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "間に　合います［時間に〜］",
      "reading": "to be on time [for an appointment, etc.]",
      "back": "間[ま]に　 合[あ]います［ 時間[じかん]に〜］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "やります",
      "reading": "To do",
      "back": "やります",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "拾います",
      "reading": "to pick up",
      "back": "拾[ひろ]います",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "連絡します",
      "reading": "to contact, get in touch with",
      "back": "連絡[れんらく]します",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "気分が　いい",
      "reading": "feel well",
      "back": "気分[きぶん]が　いい",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "気分が　惡い",
      "reading": "to feel ill",
      "back": "気分[きぶん]が　惡い",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "運動会",
      "reading": "athletic meeting, sports day",
      "back": "運動会[うんどうかい]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "盆踊り",
      "reading": "Bon Festival dance",
      "back": "盆踊[ぼんおど]り",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "フリーマーケット",
      "reading": "flea market",
      "back": "フリーマーケット",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "場所",
      "reading": "place",
      "back": "場所[ばしょ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "ボランティア",
      "reading": "volunteer",
      "back": "ボランティア",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "財布",
      "reading": "wallet, purse",
      "back": "財布[さいふ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "ごみ",
      "reading": "garbage, rubbish, dust",
      "back": "ごみ",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "国会議事堂",
      "reading": "the Diet Building",
      "back": "国会[こっかい] 議事堂[ぎじどう]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "平日",
      "reading": "weekday",
      "back": "平日[へいじつ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "〜弁",
      "reading": "~ dialect",
      "back": "〜 弁[べん]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "今度",
      "reading": "next time, another time",
      "back": "今度[こんど]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "ずいぶん",
      "reading": "very, pretty",
      "back": "ずいぶん",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "直接",
      "reading": "directly",
      "back": "直接[ちょくせつ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "いつでも",
      "reading": "any time",
      "back": "いつでも",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "どこでも",
      "reading": "anywhere",
      "back": "どこでも",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "だれでも",
      "reading": "anybody",
      "back": "だれでも",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "何でも",
      "reading": "anything",
      "back": "何[なん]でも",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "こんな〜",
      "reading": "~ like this",
      "back": "こんな〜",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "そんな〜",
      "reading": "~ like that (near the listener)",
      "back": "そんな〜",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "あんな　〜",
      "reading": "~ like that (far from both the speaker and the listener)",
      "back": "あんな　〜",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "片づきます［荷物が〜］",
      "reading": "[boxes] to be put in order, to tidy up",
      "back": "片[かた]づきます［ 荷物[にもつ]が〜］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "出します［ごみを〜］",
      "reading": "To put out [the rubbish]",
      "back": "出[だ]します［ごみを〜］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "燃える　ごみ",
      "reading": "burnable rubbish",
      "back": "燃[も]える　ごみ",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "置き場",
      "reading": "place where something is put",
      "back": "置き場[おきば]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "横",
      "reading": "side",
      "back": "横[よこ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "瓶",
      "reading": "bottle",
      "back": "瓶[びん]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "缶",
      "reading": "can",
      "back": "缶[かん]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "ガス",
      "reading": "gas",
      "back": "ガス",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "〜会社",
      "reading": "~ company",
      "back": "〜 会社[がいしゃ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "宇宙",
      "reading": "space, universe",
      "back": "宇宙[うちゅう]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "〜様",
      "reading": "Mr. ~ / Mrs. ~ (respectful equivalent of 〜さん）",
      "back": "〜 様[さま]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "宇宙船",
      "reading": "spaceship",
      "back": "宇宙船[うちゅうせん]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "怖い",
      "reading": "To be afraid of",
      "back": "怖[こわ]い",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "宇宙ステーション",
      "reading": "space station",
      "back": "宇宙[うちゅう]ステーション",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "違います",
      "reading": "To be different",
      "back": "違[ちが]います",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "宇宙飛行士",
      "reading": "astronaut",
      "back": "宇宙[うちゅう] 飛行[ひこう] 士[し]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "咲きます［花が〜］",
      "reading": "[flowers] bloom",
      "back": "咲[さ]きます［ 花[はな]が〜］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "変わります［色が〜］",
      "reading": "[the color] change",
      "back": "変[か]わります［ 色[いろ]が〜］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "困ります",
      "reading": "To be in trouble, have a problem",
      "back": "困[こま]ります",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "付けます［丸を〜］",
      "reading": "To draw [a circle], mark [with a circle], add",
      "back": "付[つ]けます［ 丸[まる]を〜］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "治ります［病気が〜］",
      "reading": "to recover from [a sickness], get well",
      "back": "治[なお]ります［ 病気[びょうき]が〜］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "直ります［故障が〜］",
      "reading": "to be fixed, be repaired",
      "back": "直[なお]ります［ 故障[こしょう]が〜］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "クリックします",
      "reading": "to click",
      "back": "クリックします",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "入力します",
      "reading": "to input",
      "back": "入力[にゅうりょく]します",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "正しい",
      "reading": "correct, right",
      "back": "正[ただ]しい",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "向こう",
      "reading": "over there, the other side",
      "back": "向[む]こう",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "島",
      "reading": "island",
      "back": "島[しま]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "港",
      "reading": "port, harbor",
      "back": "港[みなと]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "近所",
      "reading": "neighborhood, vicinity",
      "back": "近所[きんじょ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "屋上",
      "reading": "rooftop",
      "back": "屋上[おくじょう]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "海外",
      "reading": "overseas",
      "back": "海外[かいがい]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "山登り",
      "reading": "mountain climbing",
      "back": "山登[やまのぼ]り",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "歴史",
      "reading": "history",
      "back": "歴史[れきし]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "機会",
      "reading": "chance, opportunity",
      "back": "機会[きかい]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "許可",
      "reading": "permission",
      "back": "許可[きょか]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "丸",
      "reading": "circle",
      "back": "丸[まる]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "ふりがな",
      "reading": "kana above or beside kanji indicating its pronunciation",
      "back": "ふりがな",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "設備",
      "reading": "equipment, facilities",
      "back": "設備[せつび]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "レバー",
      "reading": "lever",
      "back": "レバー",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "キー",
      "reading": "key",
      "back": "キー",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "カーテン",
      "reading": "curtain",
      "back": "カーテン",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "ひも",
      "reading": "string",
      "back": "ひも",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "炊飯器",
      "reading": "rice cooker",
      "back": "炊飯[すいはん] 器[き]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "葉",
      "reading": "leaf",
      "back": "葉[は]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "昔",
      "reading": "old days, ancient times",
      "back": "昔[むかし]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "もっと",
      "reading": "more",
      "back": "もっと",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "これで　終わりましょう。",
      "reading": "Let's finish now.",
      "back": "これで　 終[お]わりましょう。",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "それなら",
      "reading": "in that case",
      "back": "それなら",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "夜行バス",
      "reading": "overnight bus",
      "back": "夜行[やこう]バス",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "旅行社",
      "reading": "travel agency",
      "back": "旅行[りょこう] 社[しゃ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "詳しい",
      "reading": "detailed",
      "back": "詳[くわ]しい",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "スキー場",
      "reading": "ski resort, ski area",
      "back": "スキー 場[じょう]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "朱",
      "reading": "vermilion",
      "back": "朱[しゅ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "交わります",
      "reading": "to keep company with",
      "back": "交[まじ]わります",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "関係",
      "reading": "relationship",
      "back": "関係[かんけい]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "仲よくします",
      "reading": "to be on good terms with",
      "back": "仲[なか]よくします",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "必要［な］",
      "reading": "necessary, essential",
      "back": "必要[ひつよう]［な］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "ことわぎ",
      "reading": "a proverb",
      "back": "ことわぎ",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "あいます［事故に〜］",
      "reading": "to encounter [an accident]",
      "back": "あいます［ 事故[じこ]に〜］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "貯金します",
      "reading": "to save money",
      "back": "貯金[ちょきん]します",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "過ぎます［７時を〜］",
      "reading": "to pass [7 o'clock]",
      "back": "過[す]ぎます［７ 時[じ]を〜］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "慣れます［仕事に〜］",
      "reading": "to get accustomed to [one's job]",
      "back": "慣[な]れます［ 仕事[しごと]に〜］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "腐ります［食べ物が〜］",
      "reading": "to [food] rot",
      "back": "腐[くさ]ります［ 食べ物[たべもの]が〜］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "剣道",
      "reading": "kendo (Japanese style fencing)",
      "back": "剣道[けんどう]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "柔道",
      "reading": "judo",
      "back": "柔道[じゅうどう]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "ラッシュ",
      "reading": "rush hour",
      "back": "ラッシュ",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "宇宙",
      "reading": "space, universe",
      "back": "宇宙[うちゅう]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "曲",
      "reading": "a piece of music",
      "back": "曲[きょく]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "毎週",
      "reading": "every week",
      "back": "毎週[まいしゅう]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "毎月",
      "reading": "every month",
      "back": "毎月[まいつき]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "毎年",
      "reading": "every year",
      "back": "毎年[まいとし]［まいねん］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "このごろ",
      "reading": "these days",
      "back": "このごろ",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "やっと",
      "reading": "finally",
      "back": "やっと",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "かなり",
      "reading": "fairly",
      "back": "かなり",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "必ず",
      "reading": "without fail, by any means",
      "back": "必[かなら]ず",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "絶対に",
      "reading": "absolutely",
      "back": "絶対[ぜったい]に",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "上手に",
      "reading": "well, skillfully",
      "back": "上手[じょうず]に",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "できるだけ",
      "reading": "as much as possible",
      "back": "できるだけ",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "ほとんど",
      "reading": "almost all (in affirmative sentences), hardly, scarcely (in negative sentences)",
      "back": "ほとんど",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "お客様",
      "reading": "visitor, guest, customer, client (respectful equivalent of おきゃくさん)",
      "back": "お 客様[きゃくさま]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "特別［な］",
      "reading": "special",
      "back": "特別[とくべつ]［な］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "して　いらっしゃいます",
      "reading": "to be doing (respectful equivalent of して　います）",
      "back": "して　いらっしゃいます",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "水泳",
      "reading": "swimming",
      "back": "水泳[すいえい]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "使って　いらっしゃるんですね。",
      "reading": "You're using, aren't you? (respectful equivalent of つかって　いるんですね）",
      "back": "使[つか]って　いらっしゃるんですね。",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "チャレンジします",
      "reading": "to challenge",
      "back": "チャレンジします",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "気持ち",
      "reading": "spirit, mood",
      "back": "気持[きも]ち",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "乗り物",
      "reading": "vehicle, means of transportation",
      "back": "乗り物[のりもの]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "ー世紀",
      "reading": "-th century",
      "back": "ー 世紀[せいき]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "遠く",
      "reading": "far, remote place",
      "back": "遠[とお]く",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "珍しい",
      "reading": "rare, uncommon",
      "back": "珍[めずら]しい",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "汽車",
      "reading": "locomotive",
      "back": "汽車[きしゃ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "汽船",
      "reading": "steam boat",
      "back": "汽船[きせん]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "大勢の　〜",
      "reading": "many (people)",
      "back": "大勢[たいせい]の　〜",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "運びます",
      "reading": "to carry, transport",
      "back": "運[はこ]びます",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "利用します",
      "reading": "to use",
      "back": "利用[りよう]します",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "自由に",
      "reading": "freely",
      "back": "自由[じゆう]に",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "飼います",
      "reading": "to keep (a pet), raise (an animal)",
      "back": "飼[か]います",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "走ります［道を］",
      "reading": "to run, drive [along a road]",
      "back": "走[はし]ります［ 道[みち]を〜］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "見えます［山が〜］",
      "reading": "[a mountain] can be seen",
      "back": "見[み]えます［ 山[やま]が〜］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "聞こえます［音が〜］",
      "reading": "[a sound] can be heard",
      "back": "聞[き]こえます［ 音[おと]が〜］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "できます［道が〜］",
      "reading": "[a road] to be made, be completed, come into existence",
      "back": "できます［ 道[みち]が〜］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "開きます［教室を〜］",
      "reading": "set up [a class], open, hold",
      "back": "開[ひら]きます［ 教室[きょうしつ]を〜］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "心配［な］",
      "reading": "worried, anxious",
      "back": "心配[しんぱい]［な］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "ペット",
      "reading": "pet",
      "back": "ペット",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "鳥",
      "reading": "bird",
      "back": "鳥[とり]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "声",
      "reading": "voice",
      "back": "声[こえ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "波",
      "reading": "wave",
      "back": "波[なみ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "花火",
      "reading": "fireworks",
      "back": "花火[はなび]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "道具",
      "reading": "tool, instrument, equipment",
      "back": "道具[どうぐ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "クリーニング",
      "reading": "(dry) cleaning, laundry",
      "back": "クリーニング",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "家",
      "reading": "house, home",
      "back": "家[いえ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "マンション",
      "reading": "condominium, apartment house, blocks of flats",
      "back": "マンション",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "キッチン",
      "reading": "kitchen",
      "back": "キッチン",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "〜教室",
      "reading": "~ class",
      "back": "〜 教室[きょうしつ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "パーティールーム",
      "reading": "party room",
      "back": "パーティールーム",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "方",
      "reading": "person (respectful equivalent of ひと)",
      "back": "方[かた]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "〜後",
      "reading": "after ~ (duration of time)",
      "back": "〜 後[ご]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "〜しか",
      "reading": "only ~ (used with negatives)",
      "back": "〜しか",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "はかの",
      "reading": "other",
      "back": "はかの",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "はっきり",
      "reading": "clearly",
      "back": "はっきり",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "家具",
      "reading": "furniture",
      "back": "家具[かぐ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "本棚",
      "reading": "bookcase",
      "back": "本棚[ほんだな]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "いつか",
      "reading": "one day, some day",
      "back": "いつか",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "建てます",
      "reading": "to build",
      "back": "建[た]てます",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "すばらしい",
      "reading": "wonderful",
      "back": "すばらしい",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "子どもたち",
      "reading": "children",
      "back": "子[こ]どもたち",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "大好き［な］",
      "reading": "like very much",
      "back": "大好[だいす]き［な］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "主人公",
      "reading": "hero, heroine",
      "back": "主人公[しゅじんこう]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "形",
      "reading": "shape",
      "back": "形[かたち]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "不思議［な］",
      "reading": "fantastic, mysterious",
      "back": "不思議[ふしぎ]［な］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "ポケット",
      "reading": "pocket",
      "back": "ポケット",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "例えば",
      "reading": "for example",
      "back": "例[たと]えば",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "付けます",
      "reading": "to attach, put on",
      "back": "付[つ]けます",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "空",
      "reading": "sky",
      "back": "空[そら]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "飛びます",
      "reading": "fly",
      "back": "飛[と]びます",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "自分",
      "reading": "oneself",
      "back": "自分[じぶん]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "将来",
      "reading": "future",
      "back": "将来[しょうらい]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "売れます ［パンが〜］",
      "reading": "to sell [bread], be sold",
      "back": "売[う]れます［パンが〜］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "踊ります",
      "reading": "to dance",
      "back": "踊[おど]ります",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "かみます",
      "reading": "to chew, bite",
      "back": "かみます",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "選びます",
      "reading": "to choose",
      "back": "選[えら]びます",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "<div>通います［大学に〜］<br></div>",
      "reading": "to go to and from [university], commute",
      "back": "通[かよ]います［ 大学[だいがく]に〜］<br>",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "メモします",
      "reading": "to take a memo",
      "back": "メモします",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "まじめ［な］",
      "reading": "serious",
      "back": "まじめ［な］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "熱心［な］",
      "reading": "earnest",
      "back": "熱心[ねっしん]［な］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "偉い",
      "reading": "great, admirable",
      "back": "偉[えら]い",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "ちょうど　いい",
      "reading": "proper, just right",
      "back": "ちょうど　いい",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "景色",
      "reading": "scenery, view",
      "back": "景色[けしき]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "美容院",
      "reading": "hair salon",
      "back": "美容[びよう] 院[いん]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "台所",
      "reading": "kitchen",
      "back": "台所[だいどころ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "経験",
      "reading": "experience (〜が　あります：to be experienced, 〜を　します：to experience)",
      "back": "経験[けいけん]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "力",
      "reading": "power",
      "back": "力[ちから]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "人気",
      "reading": "popularity (［がくせいに］〜が　あります：to be popular [with students])",
      "back": "人気[にんき]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "形",
      "reading": "form, shape",
      "back": "形[かたち]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "色",
      "reading": "color",
      "back": "色[いろ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "味",
      "reading": "taste",
      "back": "味[あじ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "ガム",
      "reading": "chewing gum",
      "back": "ガム",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "品物",
      "reading": "goods",
      "back": "品物[しなもの]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "値段",
      "reading": "price",
      "back": "値段[ねだん]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "給料",
      "reading": "salary",
      "back": "給料[きゅうりょう]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "ボーナス",
      "reading": "bonus",
      "back": "ボーナス",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "ゲーム",
      "reading": "(computer) game",
      "back": "ゲーム",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "番組",
      "reading": "program",
      "back": "番組[ばんぐみ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "ドラマ",
      "reading": "drama",
      "back": "ドラマ",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "歌手",
      "reading": "singer",
      "back": "歌手[かしゅ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "小説",
      "reading": "novel",
      "back": "小説[しょうせつ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "小説家",
      "reading": "novelist",
      "back": "小説[しょうせつ] 家[か]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "〜家",
      "reading": "-er, -ist, etc. (e.g., painter, novelist)",
      "back": "〜 家[か]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "〜機",
      "reading": "~ machine",
      "back": "〜 機[き]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "息子",
      "reading": "(my) son",
      "back": "息子[むすこ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "息子さん",
      "reading": "(someone else's) son",
      "back": "息子[むすこ]さん",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "娘",
      "reading": "(my) daugher",
      "back": "娘[むすめ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "娘さん",
      "reading": "(someone else's) daughter",
      "back": "娘[むすめ]さん",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "自分",
      "reading": "oneself",
      "back": "自分[じぶん]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "将来",
      "reading": "future",
      "back": "将来[しょうらい]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "しばらく",
      "reading": "a little while",
      "back": "しばらく",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "たいてい",
      "reading": "usually, mostly",
      "back": "たいてい",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "それに",
      "reading": "in addition",
      "back": "それに",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "それで",
      "reading": "and so",
      "back": "それで",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "［ちょっと］お願いが　あるんですが。",
      "reading": "I have a [small] favor to ask.",
      "back": "［ちょっと］お 願[ねが]いが　あるんですが。",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "実は",
      "reading": "as a matter of fact",
      "back": "実[じつ]は",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "会話",
      "reading": "conversation",
      "back": "会話[かいわ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "うーん",
      "reading": "well, let me see, hmm...",
      "back": "うーん",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "お知らせ",
      "reading": "notice",
      "back": "お 知[し]らせ",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "参加します",
      "reading": "to participate, join, attend",
      "back": "参加[さんか]します",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "日にち",
      "reading": "date",
      "back": "日[ひ]にち",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "土",
      "reading": "Saturday",
      "back": "土[ど]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "体育館",
      "reading": "gymnasium",
      "back": "体育館[たいいくかん]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "無料",
      "reading": "free of charge",
      "back": "無料[むりょう]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "誘います",
      "reading": "to invite, ask someone to join",
      "back": "誘[さそ]います",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "イベント",
      "reading": "event",
      "back": "イベント",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "開きます［ドアが〜］",
      "reading": "to open [a door]",
      "back": "開[ひら]きます［ドアが〜］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "閉まります［ドアが〜］",
      "reading": "to close, shut [a door]",
      "back": "閉[し]まります［ドアが〜］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "つきます［電気が〜］",
      "reading": "[a light] to come on, be turned on",
      "back": "つきます［ 電気[でんき]が〜］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "消えます［電気が〜］",
      "reading": "[a light] to go off",
      "back": "消[き]えます［ 電気[でんき]が〜］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "壊れます［いすが〜］",
      "reading": "to break [a chair]",
      "back": "壊[こわ]れます［いすが〜］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "割れます［コップが〜］",
      "reading": "to break [a glass], smash, shatter",
      "back": "割[わ]れます［コップが〜］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "折れます［木が〜］",
      "reading": "to break [a tree], snap",
      "back": "折[お]れます［ 木[き]が〜］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "破れます［紙が〜］",
      "reading": "to tear [paper]",
      "back": "破[やぶ]れます［ 紙[かみ]が〜］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "汚れます［服が〜］",
      "reading": "to get dirty [clothes]",
      "back": "汚[よご]れます［ 服[ふく]が〜］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "付きます［ポケットが〜］",
      "reading": "[a pocket] to be attached",
      "back": "付[つ]きます［ポケットが〜］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "外れます［ボタンが〜］",
      "reading": "[a button] to be undone",
      "back": "外[はず]れます［ボタンが〜］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "止まります［車が〜］",
      "reading": "to stop [a car], park",
      "back": "止[と]まります［ 車[くるま]が〜］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "まちがえます",
      "reading": "to make a mistake",
      "back": "まちがえます",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "落とします",
      "reading": "to drop, lose",
      "back": "落[お]とします",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "掛かります［かぎが〜］",
      "reading": "to be locked",
      "back": "掛[か]かります［かぎが〜］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "ふさます",
      "reading": "to wipe",
      "back": "ふさます",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "取り替えます",
      "reading": "to change",
      "back": "取り替[とりか]えます",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "片づけます",
      "reading": "to put (things) in order, tidy up",
      "back": "片[かた]づけます",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "［お］皿",
      "reading": "plate, dish",
      "back": "［お］ 皿[さら]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "［お］ちゃわん",
      "reading": "(rice) bowl",
      "back": "［お］ちゃわん",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "コップ",
      "reading": "glass (vessel)",
      "back": "コップ",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "ガラス",
      "reading": "glass (material)",
      "back": "ガラス",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "袋",
      "reading": "bag",
      "back": "袋[ふくろ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "書類",
      "reading": "document, papers",
      "back": "書類[しょるい]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "枝",
      "reading": "branch, twig",
      "back": "枝[えだ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "駅員",
      "reading": "station attendant",
      "back": "駅員[えきいん]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "交番",
      "reading": "police box",
      "back": "交番[こうばん]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "スピーチ",
      "reading": "speech (〜を　します：to give/make a speech)",
      "back": "スピーチ",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "返事",
      "reading": "reply, answer (〜を　します：to reply, answer)",
      "back": "返事[へんじ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "お先に　どうそ。",
      "reading": "After you. / Go ahead, please.",
      "back": "お 先[さき]に　どうそ。",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "源氏物語",
      "reading": "'The Tale of Genji' (a novel written by Murasaki Shikibu in the Heian Era)",
      "back": "源氏物語[げんじものがたり]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "今の　電車",
      "reading": "the train which has just left",
      "back": "今[いま]の　 電車[でんしゃ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "忘れ物",
      "reading": "things left behind, lost property",
      "back": "忘れ物[わすれもの]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "この　くらい",
      "reading": "about this (big)",
      "back": "この　くらい",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "〜側",
      "reading": "~ side",
      "back": "〜 側[がわ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "ポケット",
      "reading": "pocket",
      "back": "ポケット",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "〜辺",
      "reading": "\u000earound ~, ~ about",
      "back": "〜 辺[へん]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "覚えて　いません",
      "reading": "I don't remember.",
      "back": "覚[おぼ]えて　いません",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "網棚",
      "reading": "overhead rack",
      "back": "網棚[あみだな]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "確か",
      "reading": "I'm pretty sure",
      "back": "確[たし]か",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "［ああ、］よかった。",
      "reading": "[Oh,] that's great! / Thank goodness! (used to express a feeling of relief)",
      "back": "［ああ、］よかった。",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "地震",
      "reading": "earthquake",
      "back": "地震[じしん]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "壁",
      "reading": "wall",
      "back": "壁[かべ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "針",
      "reading": "hands (of a clock)",
      "back": "針[はり]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "指します",
      "reading": "to point",
      "back": "指[さ]します",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "駅前",
      "reading": "the area in front of a station",
      "back": "駅前[えきまえ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "倒れます",
      "reading": "to fall down",
      "back": "倒[たお]れます",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "西",
      "reading": "west",
      "back": "西[にし]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "〜の　方",
      "reading": "direction of ~",
      "back": "〜の　 方[ほう]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "燃えます",
      "reading": "to burn",
      "back": "燃[も]えます",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "レポーター",
      "reading": "reporter",
      "back": "レポーター",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "はります",
      "reading": "to put up, post, paste",
      "back": "はります",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "掛けます",
      "reading": "to hang",
      "back": "掛[か]けます",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "飾ります",
      "reading": "to display, decorate",
      "back": "飾[かざ]ります",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "並べます",
      "reading": "to arrange, line up",
      "back": "並[なら]べます",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "植えます",
      "reading": "to plant",
      "back": "植[う]えます",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "戻します",
      "reading": "to return, put ~ back",
      "back": "戻[もど]します",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "まとめます",
      "reading": "to put ~ together, put ~ in shape, sum up",
      "back": "まとめます",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "しまいます",
      "reading": "to put (things) away",
      "back": "しまいます",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "決めます",
      "reading": "to decide",
      "back": "決[き]めます",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "予習します",
      "reading": "to prepare one's lesson",
      "back": "予習[よしゅう]します",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "復習します",
      "reading": "to review one's lesson",
      "back": "復習[ふくしゅう]します",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "そのままに します",
      "reading": "to leave things as they are",
      "back": "そのままに　します",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "授業",
      "reading": "class",
      "back": "授業[じゅぎょう]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "講義",
      "reading": "lecture",
      "back": "講義[こうぎ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "ミーティング",
      "reading": "meeting",
      "back": "ミーティング",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "予定",
      "reading": "plan, schedule",
      "back": "予定[よてい]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "お知らせ",
      "reading": "notice",
      "back": "お 知[し]らせ",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "ガイドブック",
      "reading": "guidebook",
      "back": "ガイドブック",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "カレンダー",
      "reading": "calendar",
      "back": "カレンダー",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "ポスター",
      "reading": "poster",
      "back": "ポスター",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "予定表",
      "reading": "\u000eschedule",
      "back": "予定[よてい] 表[ひょう]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "ごみ箱",
      "reading": "trash can, dustbin",
      "back": "ごみ 箱[ばこ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "人形",
      "reading": "doll",
      "back": "人形[にんぎょう]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "花瓶",
      "reading": "vase",
      "back": "花瓶[かびん]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "鏡",
      "reading": "mirror",
      "back": "鏡[かがみ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "引き出し",
      "reading": "drawer",
      "back": "引き出[ひきだ]し",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "玄関",
      "reading": "front door, porch, entrance hall",
      "back": "玄関[げんかん]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "廊下",
      "reading": "corridor, hallway",
      "back": "廊下[ろうか]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "壁",
      "reading": "wall",
      "back": "壁[かべ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "池",
      "reading": "pond",
      "back": "池[いけ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "元の　所",
      "reading": "original place",
      "back": "元[もと]の　 所[ところ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "周り",
      "reading": "round, around",
      "back": "周[まわ]り",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "真ん中",
      "reading": "center",
      "back": "真ん中[まんなか]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "隅",
      "reading": "corner",
      "back": "隅[すみ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "まだ",
      "reading": "still",
      "back": "まだ",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "リュック",
      "reading": "rucksack",
      "back": "リュック",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "非常袋",
      "reading": "emergency kit",
      "back": "非常[ひじょう] 袋[ぶくろ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "非常時",
      "reading": "emergency",
      "back": "非常時[ひじょうじ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "生活します",
      "reading": "to live",
      "back": "生活[せいかつ]します",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "懐中電灯",
      "reading": "torch, flashlight",
      "back": "懐中[かいちゅう] 電灯[でんとう]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "〜とか、〜とか",
      "reading": "~, ~, and so on",
      "back": "〜とか、〜とか",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "丸い",
      "reading": "round",
      "back": "丸[まる]い",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "ある　〜",
      "reading": "one ~, a certain ~",
      "back": "ある　〜",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "夢を　見ます",
      "reading": "to dream",
      "back": "夢[ゆめ]を　 見[み]ます",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "うれしい",
      "reading": "glad, happy",
      "back": "うれしい",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "嫌［な］",
      "reading": "hateful, disagreeable",
      "back": "嫌[いや]［な］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "すると",
      "reading": "and, then",
      "back": "すると",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "目が　覚めます",
      "reading": "to wake up",
      "back": "目[め]が　 覚[さ]めます",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "続けます",
      "reading": "to continue",
      "back": "続[つづ]けます",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "見つけます",
      "reading": "to find",
      "back": "見[み]つけます",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "取ります［休みを〜］",
      "reading": "to take [a holiday]",
      "back": "取[と]ります［ 休[やす]みを〜］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "受けます［試験を〜］",
      "reading": "to take [an examination]",
      "back": "受[う]けます［ 試験[しけん]を〜］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "申し込みます",
      "reading": "to apply for, enter for",
      "back": "申し込[もうしこ]みます",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "休憩します",
      "reading": "to take a break, take a rest",
      "back": "休憩[きゅうけい]します",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "連休",
      "reading": "consecutive holidays",
      "back": "連休[れんきゅう]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "作文",
      "reading": "essay, composition",
      "back": "作文[さくぶん]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "発表",
      "reading": "announcement, presentation (〜します：to announce)",
      "back": "発表[はっぴょう]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "展覧会",
      "reading": "exhibition",
      "back": "展覧[てんらん] 会[かい]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "結婚式",
      "reading": "wedding ceremony",
      "back": "結婚式[けっこんしき]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "［お］葬式",
      "reading": "funeral",
      "back": "［お］ 葬式[そうしき]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "式",
      "reading": "ceremony",
      "back": "式[しき]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "本社",
      "reading": "head office (HQ)",
      "back": "本社[ほんしゃ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "支店",
      "reading": "branch office",
      "back": "支店[してん]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "教会",
      "reading": "church",
      "back": "教会[きょうかい]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "大学院",
      "reading": "graduate school",
      "back": "大学院[だいがくいん]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "動物園",
      "reading": "zoo",
      "back": "動物[どうぶつ] 園[えん]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "温泉",
      "reading": "hot spring, spa",
      "back": "温泉[おんせん]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "帰り",
      "reading": "\u000ereturn",
      "back": "帰[かえ]り",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "お子さん",
      "reading": "(someone else's) child",
      "back": "お 子[こ]さん",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "ー号",
      "reading": "train number, typhoon number, etc.",
      "back": "ー 号[ごう]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "〜の　方",
      "reading": "place toward ~, direction of ~",
      "back": "〜の　 方[ほう]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "ずっと",
      "reading": "the whole time",
      "back": "ずっと",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "バリ",
      "reading": "Bali (Indonesian island)",
      "back": "バリ",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "ピカソ",
      "reading": "Pablo Picasso, Spanish painter (1881-1973)",
      "back": "ピカソ",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "のぞみ",
      "reading": "name of a Shinkansen train (~42号：Nozomi Superexpress No. 42)",
      "back": "のぞみ",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "残ります",
      "reading": "to remain, be left, stay behind",
      "back": "残[のこ]ります",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "入学試験",
      "reading": "entrance examination",
      "back": "入学[にゅうがく] 試験[しけん]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "月に",
      "reading": "per month",
      "back": "月[つき]に",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "村",
      "reading": "village",
      "back": "村[むら]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "卒業します",
      "reading": "to graduate",
      "back": "卒業[そつぎょう]します",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "映画館",
      "reading": "movie theater, cinema",
      "back": "映画[えいが] 館[かん]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "嫌［な］",
      "reading": "hateful, disagreeable",
      "back": "嫌[いや]［な］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "空",
      "reading": "sky",
      "back": "空[そら]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "閉じます",
      "reading": "to close",
      "back": "閉[と]じます",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "都会",
      "reading": "city",
      "back": "都会[とかい]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "子どもたち",
      "reading": "children",
      "back": "子[こ]どもたち",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "自由に",
      "reading": "freely",
      "back": "自由[じゆう]に",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "運動します",
      "reading": "to (take) exercise",
      "back": "運動[うんどう]します",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "成功します",
      "reading": "to succeed",
      "back": "成功[せいこう]します",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "失敗します［試験に〜］",
      "reading": "to fail [an examination]",
      "back": "失敗[しっぱい]します［ 試験[しけん]に〜］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "合格します［試験に〜］",
      "reading": "to pass [an examination]",
      "back": "合格[ごうかく]します［ 試験[しけん]に〜］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "やみます［雨が〜］",
      "reading": "[rain] to stop",
      "back": "やみます［ 雨[あめ]が〜］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "晴れます",
      "reading": "to clear up",
      "back": "晴[は]れます",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "曇ります",
      "reading": "to get cloudy",
      "back": "曇[くも]ります",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "続きます［熱が〜］",
      "reading": "to continue [a high temperature/fever]",
      "back": "続[つづ]きます［ 熱[ねつ]が〜］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "ひきます［かぜを〜］",
      "reading": "to catch [a cold]",
      "back": "ひきます［かぜを〜］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "冷やします",
      "reading": "to cool",
      "back": "冷[ひ]やします",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "込みます［道が〜］",
      "reading": "[a road] to get crowded",
      "back": "込[こ]みます［ 道[みち]が〜］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "すきます［道が〜］",
      "reading": "[a road] to get less crowded",
      "back": "すきます［ 道[みち]が〜］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "出ます［試合に〜］［パーティーに〜］",
      "reading": "to participate [in a match]; to attend [a party]",
      "back": "出[で]ます［ 試合[しあい]に〜］［パーティーに〜］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "無理を　します",
      "reading": "to overdo things",
      "back": "無理[むり]を　します",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "十分［な］",
      "reading": "enough, sufficient",
      "back": "十分[じゅうぶん]［な］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "おかしい",
      "reading": "strange, funny",
      "back": "おかしい",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "うるさい",
      "reading": "noisy",
      "back": "うるさい",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "先生",
      "reading": "doctor",
      "back": "先生[せんせい]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "やけど",
      "reading": "burning (〜を　します：to get burned)",
      "back": "やけど",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "けが",
      "reading": "injury (〜を　します：to get injured)",
      "back": "けが",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "せき",
      "reading": "cough (〜を　します／〜が　出ます：to have a cough)",
      "back": "せき",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "インフルエンザ",
      "reading": "influenza (i.e., the flu)",
      "back": "インフルエンザ",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "空",
      "reading": "sky",
      "back": "空[そら]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "太陽",
      "reading": "sun",
      "back": "太陽[たいよう]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "星",
      "reading": "star",
      "back": "星[ほし]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "風",
      "reading": "wind",
      "back": "風[かぜ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "東",
      "reading": "east",
      "back": "東[ひがし]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "西",
      "reading": "west",
      "back": "西[にし]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "南",
      "reading": "south",
      "back": "南[みなみ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "北",
      "reading": "north",
      "back": "北[きた]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "国際　〜",
      "reading": "international ~",
      "back": "国際[こくさい]　〜",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "水道",
      "reading": "faucet, tap, water supply",
      "back": "水道[すいどう]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "エンジン",
      "reading": "engine",
      "back": "エンジン",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "チーム",
      "reading": "team",
      "back": "チーム",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "今夜",
      "reading": "this evening",
      "back": "今夜[こんや]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "夕方",
      "reading": "late afternoon",
      "back": "夕方[ゆうがた]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "まえ",
      "reading": "a time in the past, before",
      "back": "まえ",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "遅く",
      "reading": "late (time)",
      "back": "遅[おそ]く",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "こんなに",
      "reading": "this (much, etc.)",
      "back": "こんなに",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "そんなに",
      "reading": "that (much, etc.) (concerning a matter related to the listener)",
      "back": "そんなに",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "あんなに",
      "reading": "that (much, etc.) (concerning a matter not related to the speaker or the listener)",
      "back": "あんなに",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "ヨーロッパ",
      "reading": "Europe",
      "back": "ヨーロッパ",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "元気",
      "reading": "\u000evigor, energy, etc.",
      "back": "元気[げんき]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "胃",
      "reading": "stomach",
      "back": "胃[い]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "ストレス",
      "reading": "\u000estress",
      "back": "ストレス",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "それは　いけませんえ。",
      "reading": "I'm sorry to hear that.",
      "back": "それは　いけませんえ。",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "星占い",
      "reading": "horoscope",
      "back": "星[ほし] 占[うらな]い",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "牡牛座",
      "reading": "Taurus",
      "back": "牡[お] 牛[うし] 座[ざ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "働きすぎ",
      "reading": "overworking",
      "back": "働[はたら]きすぎ",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "困ります",
      "reading": "to be in trouble, have a problem",
      "back": "困[こま]ります",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "宝くじ",
      "reading": "lottery",
      "back": "宝[たから]くじ",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "当たります［宝くじが〜］",
      "reading": "to win [a lottery]",
      "back": "当[あ]たります［ 宝[たから]くじが〜］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "健康",
      "reading": "health",
      "back": "健康[けんこう]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "恋愛",
      "reading": "romantic love",
      "back": "恋愛[れんあい]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "恋人",
      "reading": "sweetheart, boyfriend, girlfriend",
      "back": "恋人[こいびと]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "ラッキーアイテム",
      "reading": "something lucky",
      "back": "ラッキーアイテム",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "石",
      "reading": "stone",
      "back": "石[いし]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "逃げます",
      "reading": "to run away",
      "back": "逃[に]げます",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "騒ぎます",
      "reading": "to make a noise",
      "back": "騒[さわ]ぎます",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "あきらめます",
      "reading": "to give up",
      "back": "あきらめます",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "投げます",
      "reading": "to throw",
      "back": "投[な]げます",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "守ります",
      "reading": "to keep, follow, obey",
      "back": "守[まも]ります",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "始まります［式が〜］",
      "reading": "[a ceremony] to begin, start",
      "back": "始[はじ]まります［ 式[しき]が〜］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "出席します",
      "reading": "to attend [a meeting]",
      "back": "出席[しゅっせき]します",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "伝えます",
      "reading": "to convey",
      "back": "伝[つた]えます",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "注意します［車に〜］",
      "reading": "to be careful [of the cars]",
      "back": "注意[ちゅうい]します［ 車[くるま]に〜］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "外します［席を〜］",
      "reading": "to be away [from one's desk]",
      "back": "外[はず]します［ 席[せき]を〜］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "戻ります",
      "reading": "to come back, return",
      "back": "戻[もど]ります",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "あります［電話が〜］",
      "reading": "to have [a telephone call]",
      "back": "あります［ 電話[でんわ]が〜］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "リサイクルします",
      "reading": "to recycle",
      "back": "リサイクルします",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "だめ［な］",
      "reading": "no good, not permitted, impossible",
      "back": "だめ［な］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "同じ",
      "reading": "same",
      "back": "同[おな]じ",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "警察",
      "reading": "police (station)",
      "back": "警察[けいさつ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "席",
      "reading": "seat",
      "back": "席[せき]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "マーク",
      "reading": "mark, symbol",
      "back": "マーク",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "ボール",
      "reading": "ball",
      "back": "ボール",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "締め切り",
      "reading": "deadline",
      "back": "締め切[しめき]り",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "規則",
      "reading": "regulation, rule",
      "back": "規則[きそく]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "危険",
      "reading": "Danger",
      "back": "危険[きけん]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "使用禁止",
      "reading": "Do Not Use",
      "back": "使用[しよう] 禁止[きんし]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "立入禁止",
      "reading": "Keep Out",
      "back": "立入禁止[たちいりきんし]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "徐行",
      "reading": "Go Slow",
      "back": "徐行[じょこう]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "入口",
      "reading": "entrance",
      "back": "入口[いりぐち]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "出口",
      "reading": "exit",
      "back": "出口[でぐち]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "非常口",
      "reading": "emergency exit",
      "back": "非常口[ひじょうぐち]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "無料",
      "reading": "Free of Charge",
      "back": "無料[むりょう]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "割引",
      "reading": "Discount",
      "back": "割引[わりびき]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "飲み放題",
      "reading": "All You Can Drink",
      "back": "飲[の]み 放題[ほうだい]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "使用中",
      "reading": "In Use",
      "back": "使用[しよう] 中[ちゅう]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "募集中",
      "reading": "Applications Wanted",
      "back": "募集[ぼしゅう] 中[ちゅう]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "〜中",
      "reading": "~ing",
      "back": "〜 中[ちゅう]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "どういう　〜",
      "reading": "what (kind of ~)",
      "back": "どういう　〜",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "いくら［〜ても］",
      "reading": "however ~, even if ~",
      "back": "いくら［〜ても］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "もう",
      "reading": "(not) any longer (used with negatives)",
      "back": "もう",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "あと　〜",
      "reading": "~ left",
      "back": "あと　〜",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "〜ほど",
      "reading": "about ~",
      "back": "〜ほど",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "駐車違反",
      "reading": "parking violation",
      "back": "駐車[ちゅうしゃ] 違反[いはん]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "罰金",
      "reading": "fine",
      "back": "罰金[ばっきん]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "地震",
      "reading": "earthquake",
      "back": "地震[じしん]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "起きます",
      "reading": "to happen",
      "back": "起[お]きます",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "助け合います",
      "reading": "to help each other",
      "back": "助け合[たすけあ]います",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "もともと",
      "reading": "originally",
      "back": "もともと",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "悲しい",
      "reading": "sad",
      "back": "悲[かな]しい",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "もっと",
      "reading": "more",
      "back": "もっと",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "あいさつ",
      "reading": "greeting, address (〜を　します：to greet, give an address)",
      "back": "あいさつ",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "相手",
      "reading": "the other person",
      "back": "相手[あいて]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "気持ち",
      "reading": "feeling",
      "back": "気持[きも]ち",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "磨きます［歯を〜］",
      "reading": "to brush [one's teeth], polish",
      "back": "磨[みが]きます［ 歯[は]を〜］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "組み立てます",
      "reading": "to assemble",
      "back": "組み立[くみた]てます",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "折ります",
      "reading": "to bend, fold, break, snap",
      "back": "折[お]ります",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "気が　つきます　［忘れ物に〜］",
      "reading": "to notice, become aware of [things left behind]",
      "back": "気[き]が　つきます　［ 忘れ物[わすれもの]に〜］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "つけます［しょうゆを〜］",
      "reading": "to put [in soy sauce]",
      "back": "つけます［しょうゆを〜］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "見つかります［かぎが〜］",
      "reading": "[a key] to be found",
      "back": "見[み]つかります［かぎが〜］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "質問します",
      "reading": "to ask a question",
      "back": "質問[しつもん]します",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "さします［傘を〜］",
      "reading": "to put up [an umbrella]",
      "back": "さします［ 傘[かさ]を〜］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "スポーツクラブ",
      "reading": "sports club",
      "back": "スポーツクラブ",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "［お］城",
      "reading": "castle",
      "back": "［お］ 城[しろ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "説明書",
      "reading": "explanatory pamphlet, instruction book",
      "back": "説明[せつめい] 書[しょ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "図",
      "reading": "figure, drawing",
      "back": "図[ず]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "線",
      "reading": "line",
      "back": "線[せん]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "矢印",
      "reading": "arrow (sign)",
      "back": "矢印[やじるし]<br>",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "黒",
      "reading": "black (noun)",
      "back": "黒[くろ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "白",
      "reading": "white (noun)",
      "back": "白[しろ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "赤",
      "reading": "red (noun)",
      "back": "赤[あか]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "青",
      "reading": "blue (noun)",
      "back": "青[あお]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "紺",
      "reading": "navy blue, dark blue (noun)",
      "back": "紺[こん]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "黄色",
      "reading": "yellow (noun)",
      "back": "黄色[きいろ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "茶色",
      "reading": "brown (noun)",
      "back": "茶色[ちゃいろ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "しょうゆ",
      "reading": "soya, soy sauce",
      "back": "しょうゆ",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "ソース",
      "reading": "sauce, Worcestershire sauce",
      "back": "ソース",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "お客［さん］",
      "reading": "visitor, guest, customer, client",
      "back": "お 客[きゃく]［さん］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "〜か　〜",
      "reading": "~ or ~",
      "back": "〜か　〜",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "ゆうべ",
      "reading": "last night",
      "back": "ゆうべ",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "さっき",
      "reading": "a short while ago",
      "back": "さっき",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "茶道",
      "reading": "tea ceremony",
      "back": "茶道[さどう]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "お茶を　たてます",
      "reading": "to make (green) tea (at a tea ceremony)",
      "back": "お 茶[ちゃ]を　たてます",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "先に",
      "reading": "first, ahead",
      "back": "先[さき]に",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "載せます",
      "reading": "place on, load onto",
      "back": "載[の]せます",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "これで　いいですか。",
      "reading": "Is this all right?",
      "back": "これで　いいですか。",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "いかがですか。",
      "reading": "How is it?",
      "back": "いかがですか。",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "苦い",
      "reading": "bitter",
      "back": "苦[にが]い",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "親子どんぶり",
      "reading": "a bowl of cooked rice with chicken and egg",
      "back": "親子[おやこ]どんぶり",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "材料",
      "reading": "material, ingredient",
      "back": "材料[ざいりょう]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "〜分",
      "reading": "portion for ~ (used for indicating quantity)",
      "back": "〜 分[ぶん]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "ーグラム",
      "reading": "- gram(s)",
      "back": "ーグラム",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "ー個",
      "reading": "counter for small objects",
      "back": "ー 個[こ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "たまねぎ",
      "reading": "onion",
      "back": "たまねぎ",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "４分の１（１／４）",
      "reading": "\u000eone fourth",
      "back": "４ 分[ぶん]の１（１／４）",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "調味料",
      "reading": "seasoning, flavouring",
      "back": "調味[ちょうみ] 料[りょう]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "適当な　大きさに",
      "reading": "in right size",
      "back": "適当[てきとう]な　 大[おお]きさに",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "なべ",
      "reading": "pan, pot",
      "back": "なべ",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "火",
      "reading": "fire, heating",
      "back": "火[ひ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "火に　かけます",
      "reading": "to put on the stove",
      "back": "火[ひ]に　かけます",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "煮ます",
      "reading": "to cook, boil",
      "back": "煮[に]ます",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "煮えます",
      "reading": "to be cooked, be boiled",
      "back": "煮[に]えます",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "どんぶり",
      "reading": "bowl",
      "back": "どんぶり",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "たちます",
      "reading": "to pass (time)",
      "back": "たちます",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "褒めます",
      "reading": "\u000eto praise",
      "back": "褒[ほ]めます",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "しかります",
      "reading": "to scold",
      "back": "しかります",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "誘います",
      "reading": "to invite, ask someone to join",
      "back": "誘[さそ]います",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "招待します",
      "reading": "to invite",
      "back": "招待[しょうたい]します",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "頼みます",
      "reading": "to ask, request",
      "back": "頼[たの]みます",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "注意します",
      "reading": "to warn, advise",
      "back": "注意[ちゅうい]します",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "とります",
      "reading": "to rob, steal",
      "back": "とります",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "踏みます",
      "reading": "to step on",
      "back": "踏[ふ]みます",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "壊します",
      "reading": "to break, destroy",
      "back": "壊[こわ]します",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "汚します",
      "reading": "to make ~ dirty",
      "back": "汚[よご]します",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "行います",
      "reading": "to hold, carry out, practise",
      "back": "行[おこな]います",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "輸出します",
      "reading": "to export",
      "back": "輸出[ゆしゅつ]します",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "輸入します",
      "reading": "to import",
      "back": "輸入[ゆにゅう]します",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "翻訳します",
      "reading": "to translate",
      "back": "翻訳[ほんやく]します",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "発明します",
      "reading": "to invent",
      "back": "発明[はつめい]します",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "発見します",
      "reading": "to discover",
      "back": "発見[はっけん]します",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "米",
      "reading": "rice",
      "back": "米[こめ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "麦",
      "reading": "barley, wheat",
      "back": "麦[むぎ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "石油",
      "reading": "oil",
      "back": "石油[せきゆ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "原料",
      "reading": "raw material",
      "back": "原料[げんりょう]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "インスタントラーメン",
      "reading": "instant noodles",
      "back": "インスタントラーメン",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "デート",
      "reading": "date",
      "back": "デート",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "泥棒",
      "reading": "thief, robber",
      "back": "泥棒[どろぼう]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "警官",
      "reading": "policeman",
      "back": "警官[けいかん]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "世界中",
      "reading": "all over the world",
      "back": "世界中[せかいじゅう]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "〜中",
      "reading": "all over ~",
      "back": "〜 中[じゅう]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "ー世紀",
      "reading": "-th century",
      "back": "ー 世紀[せいき]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "何語",
      "reading": "what language",
      "back": "何[なに] 語[ご]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "だれか",
      "reading": "somebody",
      "back": "だれか",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "よかったですね。",
      "reading": "Sounds good.",
      "back": "よかったですね。",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "オリンピック",
      "reading": "Olympic Games",
      "back": "オリンピック",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "ワールドカップ",
      "reading": "World Cup",
      "back": "ワールドカップ",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "東大寺",
      "reading": "Todaiji Temple",
      "back": "東大寺[とうだいじ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "大仏",
      "reading": "Great Buddha",
      "back": "大仏[だいぶつ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "江戸時代",
      "reading": "Edo Period (1603-1868)",
      "back": "江戸[えど] 時代[じだい]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "ポルトガル",
      "reading": "Portugal",
      "back": "ポルトガル",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "サウジアラビア",
      "reading": "Saudi Arabia",
      "back": "サウジアラビア",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "ロシア",
      "reading": "Russia",
      "back": "ロシア",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "皆様",
      "reading": "Ladies and Gentlemen, everybody (respectful equivalent of みなさん）",
      "back": "皆様[みなさま]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "焼けます［うちが〜］",
      "reading": "[house] to burn down",
      "back": "焼[や]けます［うちが〜］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "その後",
      "reading": "after that, later",
      "back": "その 後[ご]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "世界遺産",
      "reading": "World Heritage Site",
      "back": "世界[せかい] 遺産[いさん]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "〜の　一つ",
      "reading": "one of the ~",
      "back": "〜の　 一[ひと]つ",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "金色",
      "reading": "golden color",
      "back": "金色[きんいろ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "本物",
      "reading": "real thing",
      "back": "本物[ほんもの]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "金",
      "reading": "gold",
      "back": "金[きん]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "ーキロ",
      "reading": "- kilograms, - kilometers",
      "back": "ーキロ",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "美しい",
      "reading": "beautiful, pretty",
      "back": "美[うつく]しい",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "豪華［な］",
      "reading": "gorgeous",
      "back": "豪華[ごうか]［な］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "彫刻",
      "reading": "engraving, carving, sculpture",
      "back": "彫刻[ちょうこく]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "眠ります",
      "reading": "to sleep",
      "back": "眠[ねむ]ります",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "彫ります",
      "reading": "to engrave, carve",
      "back": "彫[ほ]ります",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "仲間",
      "reading": "colleague, friend",
      "back": "仲間[なかま]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "しかし",
      "reading": "however, but",
      "back": "しかし",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "その　あと",
      "reading": "after that",
      "back": "その　あと",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "一生懸命",
      "reading": "with all of one's effort",
      "back": "一生懸命[いっしょうけんめい]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "ねずみ",
      "reading": "mouse",
      "back": "ねずみ",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "一匹も　いません。",
      "reading": "There is not a single (mouse).",
      "back": "一匹[いっぴき]も　いません。",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "東照宮",
      "reading": "shrine dedicated to Tokugawa Ieyasu in Nikko, Tochigi prefecture",
      "back": "東照宮[とうしょうぐう]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "眠り猫",
      "reading": "The Sleeping Cat",
      "back": "眠[ねむ]り 猫[ねこ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "左甚五郎",
      "reading": "famous Japanese sculptor of the Edo Period (1594-1651)",
      "back": "左[ひだり] 甚[じん]五[ご]郎[ろう]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "参加します［旅行に〜］",
      "reading": "to join [a tour], participate, attend",
      "back": "参加[さんか]します［ 旅行[りょこう]に〜］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "育てます",
      "reading": "to breed, bring up",
      "back": "育[そだ]てます",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "運びます",
      "reading": "to carry, transport",
      "back": "運[はこ]びます",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "入院します",
      "reading": "to enter a hospital",
      "back": "入院[にゅういん]します",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "退院します",
      "reading": "to leave a hospital",
      "back": "退院[たいいん]します",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "入れます［電源を〜］",
      "reading": "to turn on [the power switch]",
      "back": "入[い]れます［ 電源[でんげん]を〜］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "切ります［電源を〜］",
      "reading": "to turn off [the power switch]",
      "back": "切[き]ります［ 電源[でんげん]を〜］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "掛けます［かぎを〜］",
      "reading": "to lock",
      "back": "掛[か]けます［かぎを〜］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "つきます［うそを〜］",
      "reading": "to tell [a lie]",
      "back": "つきます［うそを〜］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "気持ちが　いい",
      "reading": "pleasant, aggreeable",
      "back": "気持[きも]ちが　いい",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "気持ちが　悪い",
      "reading": "unpleasant, disgusting",
      "back": "気持[きも]ちが　 悪[わる]い",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "大きな　〜",
      "reading": "large ~, big ~",
      "back": "大[おお]きな　〜",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "小さな　〜",
      "reading": "small ~, little ~",
      "back": "小[ちい]さな　〜",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "赤ちゃん",
      "reading": "baby",
      "back": "赤[あか]ちゃん",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "小学校",
      "reading": "elementary school",
      "back": "小学校[しょうがっこう]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "中学校",
      "reading": "junior high school",
      "back": "中学校[ちゅうがっこう]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "駅前",
      "reading": "the area in front of the station",
      "back": "駅前[えきまえ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "海岸",
      "reading": "seaside, seashore",
      "back": "海岸[かいがん]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "工場",
      "reading": "factory",
      "back": "工場[こうじょう]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "村",
      "reading": "village",
      "back": "村[むら]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "かな",
      "reading": "hiragana and katakana script",
      "back": "かな",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "指輪",
      "reading": "ring",
      "back": "指輪[ゆびわ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "電源",
      "reading": "power switch",
      "back": "電源[でんげん]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "習慣",
      "reading": "habit",
      "back": "習慣[しゅうかん]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "健康",
      "reading": "health",
      "back": "健康[けんこう]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "〜製",
      "reading": "made in ~",
      "back": "〜 製[せい]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "おととし",
      "reading": "the year before last",
      "back": "おととし",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "［あ、］いけない。",
      "reading": "Oops! / Oh, no! (used when one has made a mistake)",
      "back": "［あ、］いけない。",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "お先に［失礼します］。",
      "reading": "Excuse me [for leaving before you].",
      "back": "お 先[さき]に［ 失礼[しつれい]します］。",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "原爆ドーム",
      "reading": "dome commemorating the atomic bombing of Hiroshima",
      "back": "原爆[げんばく]ドーム",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "出雲大社",
      "reading": "a shrine in Izumo city in Shinmane prefecture",
      "back": "出雲[いずも] 大社[たいしゃ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "チェンマイ",
      "reading": "Chiangmai (in Thailand)",
      "back": "チェンマイ",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "回覧",
      "reading": "circular",
      "back": "回覧[かいらん]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "研究室",
      "reading": "study room, professor's office, laboratory",
      "back": "研究[けんきゅう] 室[しつ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "きちんと",
      "reading": "neatly, tidily",
      "back": "きちんと",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "整理します",
      "reading": "sort (things) out",
      "back": "整理[せいり]します",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "方法",
      "reading": "method",
      "back": "方法[ほうほう]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "〜と　いう",
      "reading": "entitled ~, named ~, called ~",
      "back": "〜と　いう",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "ー冊",
      "reading": "counter for books, etc.",
      "back": "ー 冊[さつ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "はんこ",
      "reading": "seal, stamp",
      "back": "はんこ",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "押します［はんこを〜］",
      "reading": "to affix [a seal], stamp",
      "back": "押[お]します［はんこを〜］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "双子",
      "reading": "twins",
      "back": "双子[ふたご]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "姉妹",
      "reading": "sisters",
      "back": "姉妹[しまい]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "5年生",
      "reading": "fifth grade, fifth year",
      "back": "5 年生[ねんせい]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "似て　います",
      "reading": "to resemble, be like",
      "back": "似[に]て　います",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "性格",
      "reading": "character",
      "back": "性格[せいかく]<br>",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "おとなしい",
      "reading": "quiet, gentle",
      "back": "おとなしい",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "優しい",
      "reading": "kind, gentle, tender-hearted",
      "back": "優[やさ]しい",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "世話を　します",
      "reading": "to take care of",
      "back": "世話[せわ]を　します",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "時間が　たちます",
      "reading": "time passes by",
      "back": "時間[じかん]が　たちます",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "大好き［な］",
      "reading": "like very much",
      "back": "大好[だいす]き［な］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "ー点",
      "reading": "- points",
      "back": "ー 点[てん]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "気が　強い",
      "reading": "tough, strong-willed",
      "back": "気[き]が　 強[つよ]い",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "けんかします",
      "reading": "to quarrel, fight",
      "back": "けんかします",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "不思議［な］",
      "reading": "mysterious, strange",
      "back": "不思議[ふしぎ]［な］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "年齢",
      "reading": "age",
      "back": "年齢[ねんれい]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "しかた",
      "reading": "way (of doing something)",
      "back": "しかた",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "答えます［質問に〜］",
      "reading": "to answer [a question]",
      "back": "答[こた]えます［ 質問[しつもん]に〜］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "倒れます［ビルが〜］",
      "reading": "[a building] to fall down",
      "back": "倒[たお]れます［ビルが〜］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "通ります［道を〜］",
      "reading": "to pass [along a stree]",
      "back": "通[とお]ります［ 道[みち]を〜］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "死にます",
      "reading": "to die",
      "back": "死[し]にます",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "びっくりします",
      "reading": "to be surprised",
      "back": "びっくりします",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "がっかりします",
      "reading": "to be disappointed",
      "back": "がっかりします",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "安心します",
      "reading": "to be relieved",
      "back": "安心[あんしん]します",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "けんかします",
      "reading": "to quarrel, fight",
      "back": "けんかします",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "離婚します",
      "reading": "to divorce",
      "back": "離婚[りこん]します",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "太ります",
      "reading": "to get fat, gain weight",
      "back": "太[ふと]ります",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "やせます",
      "reading": "to get slim, lose weight",
      "back": "やせます",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "複雑［な］",
      "reading": "complicated, complex",
      "back": "複雑[ふくざつ]［な］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "邪魔［な］",
      "reading": "obstructive, in the way",
      "back": "邪魔[じゃま]［な］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "硬い",
      "reading": "hard, tough, solid",
      "back": "硬[かた]い",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "軟らかい",
      "reading": "soft, tender",
      "back": "軟[やわ]らかい",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "汚い",
      "reading": "dirty",
      "back": "汚[きたな]い",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "うれしい",
      "reading": "glad, happy",
      "back": "うれしい",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "悲しい",
      "reading": "sad",
      "back": "悲[かな]しい",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "恥ずかしい",
      "reading": "embarrassed, ashamed",
      "back": "恥[は]ずかしい",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "首相",
      "reading": "Prime Minister",
      "back": "首相[しゅしょう]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "首相",
      "reading": "earthquake",
      "back": "首相[しゅしょう]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "津波",
      "reading": "tsunami, tidal wave",
      "back": "津波[つなみ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "台風",
      "reading": "typhoon",
      "back": "台風[たいふう]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "雷",
      "reading": "thunder",
      "back": "雷[かみなり]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "火事",
      "reading": "fire",
      "back": "火事[かじ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "事故",
      "reading": "accident",
      "back": "事故[じこ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "ハイキング",
      "reading": "hiking",
      "back": "ハイキング",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "［お］見合い",
      "reading": "a meeting arranged with a view to marriage",
      "back": "［お］ 見合[みあ]い",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "操作",
      "reading": "operation (〜します：to operate)",
      "back": "操作[そうさ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "会場",
      "reading": "venue, event location",
      "back": "会場[かいじょう]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "〜代",
      "reading": "charge, fare, fee",
      "back": "〜 代[だい]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "〜屋",
      "reading": "-er (e.g., bak<u>er</u>, groc<u>er</u>, etc.)",
      "back": "〜 屋[や]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "フロント",
      "reading": "front desk, reception desk",
      "back": "フロント",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "ー号室",
      "reading": "room number -",
      "back": "ー 号[ごう] 室[しつ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "タオル",
      "reading": "towel",
      "back": "タオル",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "せっけん",
      "reading": "soap",
      "back": "せっけん",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "大勢",
      "reading": "a great number (of people)",
      "back": "大勢[おおせい]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "お疲れ様でした。",
      "reading": "Thank you for your hard work. (used to express appreciation for a coleague's or subordinate's work)",
      "back": "お 疲れ様[つかれさま]でした。",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "伺います。",
      "reading": "I'm coming. (humble equivalent of 行きます\u000e)",
      "back": "伺[うかが]います。",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "途中で",
      "reading": "on the way, in the midst of",
      "back": "途中[とちゅう]で",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "トラック",
      "reading": "truck, lorry",
      "back": "トラック",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "ぶつかります",
      "reading": "to bump, collide",
      "back": "ぶつかります",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "大人",
      "reading": "adult",
      "back": "大人[おとな]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "しかし",
      "reading": "however, but",
      "back": "しかし",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "また",
      "reading": "and",
      "back": "また",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "洋服",
      "reading": "Western clothes",
      "back": "洋服[ようふく]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "西洋化します",
      "reading": "to be Westernized",
      "back": "西洋[せいよう] 化[か]します",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "合います",
      "reading": "to fit, suit",
      "back": "合[あ]います",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "今では",
      "reading": "now",
      "back": "今[いま]では",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "成人式",
      "reading": "coming-of-age celebration",
      "back": "成人[せいじん] 式[しき]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "伝統的［な］",
      "reading": "traditional",
      "back": "伝統[でんとう] 的[てき]［な］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "数えます",
      "reading": "to count",
      "back": "数[かぞ]えます",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "測ります、量ります",
      "reading": "to measure, weigh",
      "back": "測[はか]ります、 量[はか]ります",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "確かめます",
      "reading": "to confirm, make sure",
      "back": "確[たし]かめます",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "合います［サイズが〜］",
      "reading": "[the size] to fit",
      "back": "合[あ]います［サイズが〜］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "出発します",
      "reading": "to depart",
      "back": "出発[しゅっぱつ]します",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "到着します",
      "reading": "to arrive",
      "back": "到着[とうちゃく]します",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "酔います",
      "reading": "to get drunk",
      "back": "酔[よ]います",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "うまく　いきます",
      "reading": "to go well",
      "back": "うまく　いきます",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "出ます［問題が〜］",
      "reading": "[problems] to be on a test",
      "back": "出[で]ます［ 問題[もんだい]が〜］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "相談します",
      "reading": "to consult, discuss",
      "back": "相談[そうだん]します",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "必要［な］",
      "reading": "necessary",
      "back": "必要[ひつよう]［な］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "天気予報",
      "reading": "weather forecast",
      "back": "天気[てんき] 予報[よほう]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "忘年会",
      "reading": "year-end party",
      "back": "忘年会[ぼうねんかい]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "新年会",
      "reading": "New Year's party",
      "back": "新年[しんねん] 会[かい]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "二次会",
      "reading": "second party",
      "back": "二次会[にじかい]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "発表会",
      "reading": "presentation meeting",
      "back": "発表[はっぴょう] 会[かい]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "大会",
      "reading": "rally, convention",
      "back": "大会[たいかい]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "マラソン",
      "reading": "marathon",
      "back": "マラソン",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "コンテスト",
      "reading": "contest",
      "back": "コンテスト",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "表",
      "reading": "face, front",
      "back": "表[おもて]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "裏",
      "reading": "back (side)",
      "back": "裏[うら]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "まちがい",
      "reading": "mistake",
      "back": "まちがい",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "傷",
      "reading": "defect, wound, scratch",
      "back": "傷[きず]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "ズボン",
      "reading": "trousers",
      "back": "ズボン",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "［お］年寄り",
      "reading": "elderly person",
      "back": "［お］ 年寄[としよ]り",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "長さ",
      "reading": "length",
      "back": "長[なが]さ",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "重さ",
      "reading": "weight",
      "back": "重[おも]さ",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "高さ",
      "reading": "height",
      "back": "高[たか]さ",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "大きさ",
      "reading": "size, scale",
      "back": "大[おお]きさ",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "［ー］便",
      "reading": "flight, flight number",
      "back": "［ー］ 便[びん]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "ー個",
      "reading": "counter for small objects",
      "back": "ー 個[こ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "ー本 　(ーぽん、ーぼん）",
      "reading": "counter for long objects",
      "back": "ー 本[ほん]　(ーぽん、ーぼん）",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "ー杯（ーぱい、ーばい）",
      "reading": "- glass or cup of (counter for full cups, glasses, etc.)",
      "back": "ー 杯[はい]（ーぱい、ーばい）",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "ーセンチ",
      "reading": "- centimeters",
      "back": "ーセンチ",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "ーミリ",
      "reading": "- millimeters&nbsp;",
      "back": "ーミリ",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "ーグラム",
      "reading": "- grams",
      "back": "ーグラム",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "〜以上",
      "reading": "not less than ~, over ~",
      "back": "〜 以上[いじょう]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "〜以下",
      "reading": "not more than ~, under ~",
      "back": "〜 以下[いか]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "長崎",
      "reading": "capital of Nagasaki prefecture",
      "back": "長崎[ながさき]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "仙台",
      "reading": "capital of Miyagi prefecture",
      "back": "仙台[せんだい]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "JAL",
      "reading": "Japan Airlines",
      "back": "JAL",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "七夕祭り",
      "reading": "the Star Festival",
      "back": "七夕[たなばた] 祭[まつ]り",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "東照宮",
      "reading": "shrine dedicated to Tokugawa Ieyasu in Nikko, Tochigi prefecture",
      "back": "東照宮[とうしょうぐう]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "どうでしょうか。",
      "reading": "How is ~? (polite equivalent of どうですか)",
      "back": "どうでしょうか。",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "テスト",
      "reading": "test, examination",
      "back": "テスト",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "成績",
      "reading": "performance, score, result",
      "back": "成績[せいせき]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "ところで",
      "reading": "by the way",
      "back": "ところで",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "いらっしゃいます",
      "reading": "to come (respectful equivalent of きます)",
      "back": "いらっしゃいます",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "様子",
      "reading": "situation, condition, appearance",
      "back": "様子[ようす]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "事件",
      "reading": "incident, case",
      "back": "事件[じけん]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "オートバイ",
      "reading": "motorcycle",
      "back": "オートバイ",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "僕弾",
      "reading": "bomb",
      "back": "僕[ぼく] 弾[だん]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "積みます",
      "reading": "to load, pile up",
      "back": "積[つ]みます",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "運転手",
      "reading": "driver",
      "back": "運転[うんてん] 手[しゅ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "離れた",
      "reading": "remote",
      "back": "離[はな]れた",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "急に",
      "reading": "suddenly",
      "back": "急[きゅう]に",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "動かします",
      "reading": "to start, operate, move",
      "back": "動[うご]かします",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "一生懸命",
      "reading": "with all of one's effort",
      "back": "一生懸命[いっしょうけんめい]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "犯人",
      "reading": "offender, criminal",
      "back": "犯人[はんにん]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "男",
      "reading": "man",
      "back": "男[おとこ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "手に　入れます",
      "reading": "to obtain, get",
      "back": "手[て]に　 入[い]れます",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "今でも",
      "reading": "even now",
      "back": "今[いま]でも",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "いただきます",
      "reading": "to receive (humble equivalent of もらいます)",
      "back": "いただきます",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "くださいます",
      "reading": "to give (respectful equivalent of くれます)",
      "back": "くださいます",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "やります",
      "reading": "to give (to a younger person, subordinate, animals or plants)",
      "back": "やります",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "上げます",
      "reading": "to raise, lift up",
      "back": "上[あ]げます",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "下げます",
      "reading": "to lower, pull down",
      "back": "下[さ]げます",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "親切に　します",
      "reading": "to be kind to",
      "back": "親切[しんせつ]に　します",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "かわいい",
      "reading": "lovely, cute",
      "back": "かわいい",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "珍しい",
      "reading": "rare, uncommon",
      "back": "珍[めずら]しい",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "お祝い",
      "reading": "celebration, gift (〜を　します：\u000eto celebrate)",
      "back": "お 祝[いわ]い",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "お年玉",
      "reading": "money given as a New Year's gift",
      "back": "お 年玉[としだま]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "［お］見舞い",
      "reading": "expression of sympathy, consolatory gift to a sick person",
      "back": "［お］ 見舞[みま]い",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "興味",
      "reading": "interest (［コンピューターに］〜が　あります：to be interested [in computers])",
      "back": "興味[きょうみ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "情報",
      "reading": "information",
      "back": "情報[じょうほう]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "文法",
      "reading": "grammar",
      "back": "文法[ぶんぽう]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "発音",
      "reading": "pronunciation",
      "back": "発音[はつおん]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "猿",
      "reading": "ape, monkey",
      "back": "猿[さる]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "えさ",
      "reading": "feed, bait",
      "back": "えさ",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "おもちゃ",
      "reading": "toy",
      "back": "おもちゃ",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "絵本",
      "reading": "picture book",
      "back": "絵本[えほん]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "絵はがき",
      "reading": "picture postcard",
      "back": "絵[え]はがき",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "ドライバー",
      "reading": "screwdriver",
      "back": "ドライバー",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "ハンカチ",
      "reading": "handkerchief",
      "back": "ハンカチ",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "靴下",
      "reading": "socks, stockings",
      "back": "靴下[くつした]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "手袋",
      "reading": "gloves",
      "back": "手袋[てぶくろ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "幼稚園",
      "reading": "preschool, kindergarten",
      "back": "幼稚園[ようちえん]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "暖房",
      "reading": "heating",
      "back": "暖房[だんぼう]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "冷房",
      "reading": "air-conditioning",
      "back": "冷房[れいぼう]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "温度",
      "reading": "temperature",
      "back": "温度[おんど]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "祖父",
      "reading": "(my) grandfather",
      "back": "祖父[そふ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "祖母",
      "reading": "(my) grandmother",
      "back": "祖母[そぼ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "孫",
      "reading": "(my) grandchild",
      "back": "孫[まご]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "お孫さん",
      "reading": "(someone else's) grandchild",
      "back": "お 孫[まご]さん",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "おじ",
      "reading": "my (uncle)",
      "back": "おじ",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "おじさん",
      "reading": "(someone else's) uncle",
      "back": "おじさん",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "おば",
      "reading": "(my) aunt",
      "back": "おば",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "おばさん",
      "reading": "(someone else's) aunt",
      "back": "おばさん",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "管理人",
      "reading": "janitor, caretaker",
      "back": "管理[かんり] 人[じん]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "〜さん",
      "reading": "suffix added to a person's job title as a polite way of referring to them",
      "back": "〜さん",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "この間",
      "reading": "the other day",
      "back": "この 間[あいだ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "ひとこと",
      "reading": "a few words",
      "back": "ひとこと",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "〜ずつ",
      "reading": "each",
      "back": "〜ずつ",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "二人",
      "reading": "couple",
      "back": "二人[ふたり]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "お宅",
      "reading": "home (respectful equivalent of うち or いえ)",
      "back": "お 宅[たく]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "とうぞ　お幸せに。",
      "reading": "I hope you will be very happy.",
      "back": "とうぞ　お 幸[しあわ]せに。",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "昔話",
      "reading": "old tale, folklore",
      "back": "昔話[むかしばなし]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "ある　〜",
      "reading": "a certain ~, one ~",
      "back": "ある　〜",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "男",
      "reading": "man",
      "back": "男[おとこ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "子どもたち",
      "reading": "children",
      "back": "子[こ]どもたち",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "いじめます",
      "reading": "to bully, abuse, ill-treat",
      "back": "いじめます",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "かめ",
      "reading": "turtle, tortoise",
      "back": "かめ",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "助けます",
      "reading": "to save, help",
      "back": "助[たす]けます",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "優しい",
      "reading": "kind, gentle, tender-hearted",
      "back": "優[やさ]しい",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "お姫様",
      "reading": "princess",
      "back": "お 姫様[ひめさま]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "暮らします",
      "reading": "to live, lead a life",
      "back": "暮[く]らします",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "陸",
      "reading": "land, shore",
      "back": "陸[りく]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "すると",
      "reading": "and, then",
      "back": "すると",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "煙",
      "reading": "smoke",
      "back": "煙[けむり]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "真っ白［な］",
      "reading": "pure white",
      "back": "真っ白[まっしろ]［な］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "中身",
      "reading": "content",
      "back": "中身[なかみ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "浦島太郎",
      "reading": "name of the main character in an old folk tale",
      "back": "浦島[うらしま] 太郎[たろう]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "包みます",
      "reading": "to wrap",
      "back": "包[つつ]みます",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "沸かします",
      "reading": "to boil",
      "back": "沸[わ]かします",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "混ぜます",
      "reading": "to mix",
      "back": "混[ま]ぜます",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "計算します",
      "reading": "to calculate",
      "back": "計算[けいさん]します",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "並びます",
      "reading": "to stand in a queue, line up",
      "back": "並[なら]びます",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "丈夫［な］",
      "reading": "strong, healthy",
      "back": "丈夫[じょうぶ]［な］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "アパート",
      "reading": "apartment, flat",
      "back": "アパート",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "弁護士",
      "reading": "lawyer, attorney, solicitor, barrister",
      "back": "弁護士[べんごし]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "音楽家",
      "reading": "musician",
      "back": "音楽家[おんがくか]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "子どもたち",
      "reading": "children",
      "back": "子[こ]どもたち",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "自然",
      "reading": "nature",
      "back": "自然[しぜん]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "教育",
      "reading": "education",
      "back": "教育[きょういく]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "文化",
      "reading": "culture",
      "back": "文化[ぶんか]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "社会",
      "reading": "society",
      "back": "社会[しゃかい]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "政治",
      "reading": "politics",
      "back": "政治[せいじ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "法律",
      "reading": "law",
      "back": "法律[ほうりつ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "戦争",
      "reading": "war",
      "back": "戦争[せんそう]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "平和",
      "reading": "peace",
      "back": "平和[へいわ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "目的",
      "reading": "purpose",
      "back": "目的[もくてき]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "論文",
      "reading": "thesis, academic paper",
      "back": "論文[ろんぶん]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "楽しみ",
      "reading": "pleasure, enjoyment, expectation",
      "back": "楽[たの]しみ",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "ミキサー",
      "reading": "mixer, blender",
      "back": "ミキサー",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "やかん",
      "reading": "kettle",
      "back": "やかん",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "ふた",
      "reading": "lid, cover, cap",
      "back": "ふた",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "栓抜き",
      "reading": "bottle opener, corkscrew",
      "back": "栓[せん] 抜[ぬ]き",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "缶切り",
      "reading": "can opener",
      "back": "缶切[かんき]り",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "缶詰",
      "reading": "canned food, tinned food",
      "back": "缶詰[かんづめ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "のし袋",
      "reading": "envelop for a gift of money",
      "back": "のし 袋[ぶくろ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "ふろしき",
      "reading": "wrapping cloth used to carry things",
      "back": "ふろしき",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "そろばん",
      "reading": "abacus",
      "back": "そろばん",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "体温計",
      "reading": "(clinical) thermometer",
      "back": "体温計[たいおんけい]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "材料",
      "reading": "material, ingredient",
      "back": "材料[ざいりょう]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "ある　〜",
      "reading": "a certain ~, one ~",
      "back": "ある　〜",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "一生懸命",
      "reading": "with all of one's effort",
      "back": "一生懸命[いっしょうけんめい]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "なぜ",
      "reading": "why",
      "back": "なぜ",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "どのくらい",
      "reading": "how much, how many",
      "back": "どのくらい",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "国連",
      "reading": "United Nations",
      "back": "国連[こくれん]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "エリーゼの　ために",
      "reading": "Für Elise (For Elise)",
      "back": "エリーゼの　ために",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "ベートーベン",
      "reading": "Ludwig van Beethoven, German composer (1770-1827)",
      "back": "ベートーベン",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "出ます［ボーナスが〜］",
      "reading": "[bonus] to be paid",
      "back": "出[で]ます［ボーナスが〜］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "半分",
      "reading": "half",
      "back": "半分[はんぶん]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "ローン",
      "reading": "loan",
      "back": "ローン",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "カップめん",
      "reading": "instant noodles sold in a ready-to-use disposable container, pot noodles",
      "back": "カップ[かっぷ]めん",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "世界初",
      "reading": "world's first",
      "back": "世界[せかい] 初[はつ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "〜に　よって",
      "reading": "by ~",
      "back": "〜に　よって",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "どんぶり",
      "reading": "bowl",
      "back": "どんぶり",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "めん",
      "reading": "noodles",
      "back": "めん",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "広めます",
      "reading": "to spread",
      "back": "広[ひろ]めます",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "市場調査",
      "reading": "market survey, market research",
      "back": "市場[しじょう] 調査[ちょうさ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "割ります",
      "reading": "to break",
      "back": "割[わ]ります",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "注ぎます",
      "reading": "to pour",
      "back": "注[そそ]ぎます",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "チキンラーメン",
      "reading": "brand name of instant noodles",
      "back": "チキンラーメン",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "安藤百福",
      "reading": "Japanese businessman and inventor (1910-2007)",
      "back": "安藤[あんどう] 百[もも] 福[ふく]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "増えます［輸出が〜］",
      "reading": "[exports] to increase",
      "back": "増[ふ]えます［ 輸出[ゆしゅつ]が〜］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "減ります［輸出が〜］",
      "reading": "[exports] to decrease",
      "back": "減[へ]ります［ 輸出[ゆしゅつ]が〜］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "上がります［値段が〜］",
      "reading": "[the price] to rise",
      "back": "上[あ]がります［ 値段[ねだん]が〜］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "下がります［値段が〜］",
      "reading": "[the price] to fall, drop",
      "back": "下[さ]がります［ 値段[ねだん]が〜］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "切れます［ひもが〜］",
      "reading": "[a string] to break, snap",
      "back": "切[き]れます［ひもが〜］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "とれます［ボタンが〜］",
      "reading": "[a button] to come off",
      "back": "とれます［ボタンが〜］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "落ちます［荷物が〜］",
      "reading": "[baggage] to fall down",
      "back": "落[お]ちます［ 荷物[にもつ]が〜］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "なくなります［ガソリンが〜］",
      "reading": "[petrol, gasoline] to run out, be lost",
      "back": "なくなります［ガソリンが〜］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "変［な］",
      "reading": "strange, peculiar",
      "back": "変[へん]［な］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "幸せ［な］",
      "reading": "happy",
      "back": "幸[しあわ]せ［な］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "楽［な］",
      "reading": "easy",
      "back": "楽[らく]［な］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "うまい",
      "reading": "tasty",
      "back": "うまい",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "まずい",
      "reading": "not tasty",
      "back": "まずい",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "つまらない",
      "reading": "boring, uninteresting, trivial",
      "back": "つまらない",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "優しい",
      "reading": "kind, gentle, tender-hearted",
      "back": "優[やさ]しい",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "ガソリン",
      "reading": "petrol, gasoline",
      "back": "ガソリン",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "火",
      "reading": "fire",
      "back": "火[ひ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "パンフレット",
      "reading": "pamphlet",
      "back": "パンフレット",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "今にも",
      "reading": "at any moment (used to describe a situation just before it changes)",
      "back": "今[いま]にも",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "わあ",
      "reading": "Oh! / Wow!",
      "back": "わあ",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "ばら",
      "reading": "rose",
      "back": "ばら",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "ドライブ",
      "reading": "driving",
      "back": "ドライブ",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "理由",
      "reading": "reason",
      "back": "理由[りゆう]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "謝ります",
      "reading": "to apologize",
      "back": "謝[あやま]ります",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "知り合います",
      "reading": "to get acquainted",
      "back": "知り合[しりあ]います",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "泣きます",
      "reading": "to cry",
      "back": "泣[な]きます",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "笑います",
      "reading": "to laugh, smile",
      "back": "笑[わら]います",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "眠ります",
      "reading": "to sleep",
      "back": "眠[ねむ]ります",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "乾きます［シャツが〜］",
      "reading": "[a shirt] to dry",
      "back": "乾[かわ]きます［シャツが〜］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "ぬれます［シャツが〜］",
      "reading": "[a shirt] to get wet",
      "back": "ぬれます［シャツが〜］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "滑ります",
      "reading": "to slip",
      "back": "滑[すべ]ります",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "起きます［事故が〜］",
      "reading": "[an accident] to happen",
      "back": "起[お]きます［ 事故[じこ]が〜］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "調節します",
      "reading": "to adjust",
      "back": "調節[ちょうせつ]します",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "安全［な］",
      "reading": "safe",
      "back": "安全[あんぜん]［な］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "危険［な］",
      "reading": "dangerous",
      "back": "危険[きけん]［な］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "濃い",
      "reading": "strong (taste), dark (color), thick (liquid)",
      "back": "濃[こ]い",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "薄い",
      "reading": "weak (taste), light (color), thin",
      "back": "薄[うす]い",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "厚い",
      "reading": "thick",
      "back": "厚[あつ]い",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "太い",
      "reading": "thick (of a large diameter)",
      "back": "太[ふと]い",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "細い",
      "reading": "thin (of a small diameter)",
      "back": "細[ほそ]い",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "空気",
      "reading": "air",
      "back": "空気[くうき]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "涙",
      "reading": "tear",
      "back": "涙[なみだ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "和食",
      "reading": "Japanese dish",
      "back": "和食[わしょく]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "洋食",
      "reading": "Western dish",
      "back": "洋食[ようしょく]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "おかず",
      "reading": "side dish",
      "back": "おかず",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "量",
      "reading": "quantity",
      "back": "量[りょう]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "ー倍",
      "reading": "- times",
      "back": "ー 倍[ばい]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "シングル",
      "reading": "single room",
      "back": "シングル",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "ツイン",
      "reading": "twin-bedded room",
      "back": "ツイン",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "洗濯物",
      "reading": "washing, laundry",
      "back": "洗濯[せんたく] 物[ぶつ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "DVD",
      "reading": "DVD",
      "back": "DVD",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "どう　なさいますか。",
      "reading": "What can I do for you? (respectful)",
      "back": "どう　なさいますか。",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "カット",
      "reading": "haircut",
      "back": "カット",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "シャンプー",
      "reading": "shampoo (〜を　します：to shampoo)",
      "back": "シャンプー",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "どういうふうに　なさいますか。",
      "reading": "How would you like it done? (respectful)",
      "back": "どういうふうに　なさいますか。",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "ショート",
      "reading": "short",
      "back": "ショート",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "〜みたいに　して　ください。",
      "reading": "Do it like ~.",
      "back": "〜みたいに　して　ください。",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "これで　よろしいでしょうか。",
      "reading": "Would this be alright? (polite)",
      "back": "これで　よろしいでしょうか。",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "［どうも］お疲れ様でした。",
      "reading": "Thank you for your patience. (shop assistant to customer)",
      "back": "［どうも］お 疲れ様[つかれさま]でした。",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "嫌がります",
      "reading": "to dislike",
      "back": "嫌[いや]がります",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "また",
      "reading": "and",
      "back": "また",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "うまく",
      "reading": "well",
      "back": "うまく",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "順序",
      "reading": "order",
      "back": "順序[じゅんじょ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "安心［な］",
      "reading": "relieved",
      "back": "安心[あんしん]［な］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "表現",
      "reading": "expression",
      "back": "表現[ひょうげん]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "例えば",
      "reading": "for example",
      "back": "例[たと]えば",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "別れます",
      "reading": "to part, separate",
      "back": "別[わか]れます",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "これら",
      "reading": "these",
      "back": "これら",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "縁起が　悪い",
      "reading": "unlucky, ill-omened",
      "back": "縁起[えんぎ]が　 悪[わる]い",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "信じます",
      "reading": "to believe, trust",
      "back": "信[しん]じます",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "カンセルします",
      "reading": "to cancel",
      "back": "カンセルします",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "知らせます",
      "reading": "to inform",
      "back": "知[し]らせます",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "保証書",
      "reading": "guarantee",
      "back": "保証書[ほしょうしょ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "領収書",
      "reading": "receipt",
      "back": "領収[りょうしゅう] 書[しょ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "カンプ",
      "reading": "camp",
      "back": "カンプ",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "中止",
      "reading": "calling off, cancelling, suspension",
      "back": "中止[ちゅうし]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "点",
      "reading": "point, score",
      "back": "点[てん]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "梅",
      "reading": "plum (blossom)",
      "back": "梅[うめ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "１１０番",
      "reading": "the emergency police telephone number",
      "back": "１１０ 番[ばん]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "１１９番",
      "reading": "the emergency fire service telephone number",
      "back": "１１９ 番[ばん]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "急に",
      "reading": "suddenly",
      "back": "急[きゅう]に",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "無理に",
      "reading": "unreasonably",
      "back": "無理[むり]に",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "楽しみに　して　います",
      "reading": "to be looking forward to, be expecting",
      "back": "楽[たの]しみに　して　います",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "以上です",
      "reading": "That's all.",
      "back": "以上[いじょう]です",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "係員",
      "reading": "person in charge, organiser",
      "back": "係員[かかりいん]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "コース",
      "reading": "course, route",
      "back": "コース",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "スタート",
      "reading": "start",
      "back": "スタート",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "ー位",
      "reading": "-th (ranking)",
      "back": "ー 位[い]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "優勝します",
      "reading": "to win the championship, come first",
      "back": "優勝[ゆうしょう]します<br>",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "悩み",
      "reading": "trouble, worry",
      "back": "悩[なや]み",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "目覚まし［時計］",
      "reading": "alarm clock",
      "back": "目覚[めざ]まし［ 時計[どけい]］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "目が　覚めます",
      "reading": "to wake up",
      "back": "目[め]が　 覚[さ]めます",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "大学生",
      "reading": "university student",
      "back": "大学生[だいがくせい]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "回答",
      "reading": "answer, reply (〜します：to answer, reply)",
      "back": "回答[かいとう]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "鳴ります",
      "reading": "to ring",
      "back": "鳴[な]ります",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "セットします",
      "reading": "to set",
      "back": "セットします",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "それでも",
      "reading": "nevertheless, for all that",
      "back": "それでも",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "渡します",
      "reading": "to hand over",
      "back": "渡[わた]します",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "帰って　来ます",
      "reading": "to come back",
      "back": "帰[かえ]って　 来[き]ます",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "出ます［バスが〜］",
      "reading": "[a bus] to leave, depart",
      "back": "出[で]ます［バスが〜］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "届きます［荷物が〜］",
      "reading": "[parcels] to be delivered",
      "back": "届[とど]きます［ 荷物[にもつ]が〜］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "入学します［大学に〜］",
      "reading": "to enter [a university]",
      "back": "入学[にゅうがく]します［ 大学[だいがく]に〜］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "卒業します［大学を〜］",
      "reading": "to graduate [from a university]",
      "back": "卒業[そつぎょう]します［ 大学[だいがく]を〜］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "焼きます",
      "reading": "to bake, grill, roast",
      "back": "焼[や]きます",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "焼けます［パンが〜］［肉が〜］",
      "reading": "[bread] to be baked, [meat] to be roasted, be grilled",
      "back": "焼[や]けます［パンが〜］［ 肉[にく]が〜］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "留守",
      "reading": "absence",
      "back": "留守[るす]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "宅配便",
      "reading": "(package delivered by) home delivery service",
      "back": "宅配[たくはい] 便[びん]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "原因",
      "reading": "cause",
      "back": "原因[げんいん]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "こちら",
      "reading": "my side",
      "back": "こちら",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "〜の　所",
      "reading": "where ~ is/are, by the ~",
      "back": "〜の　 所[ところ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "半年",
      "reading": "half a year",
      "back": "半年[はんとし]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "ちょうど",
      "reading": "just, exactly",
      "back": "ちょうど",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "たった今",
      "reading": "just now (used with the past tense; indicates completion)",
      "back": "たった 今[いま]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "今　いいですか。",
      "reading": "Have you got a moment?",
      "back": "今[いま]　いいですか。",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "ガスサーセンター",
      "reading": "gas service center",
      "back": "ガスサーセンター",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "ガスレンジ",
      "reading": "gas range, gas cooker",
      "back": "ガスレンジ",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "具合",
      "reading": "condition",
      "back": "具合[ぐあい]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "申し訳ありません。",
      "reading": "I'm sorry.",
      "back": "申し訳[もうしわけ]ありません。",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "どちら様でしょうか。",
      "reading": "Who is this, please?",
      "back": "どちら 様[さま]でしょうか。",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "お待たせしました。",
      "reading": "Sorry to have kept you waiting.",
      "back": "お 待[ま]たせしました。",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "向かいます",
      "reading": "to head for",
      "back": "向[む]かいます",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "ついて　います",
      "reading": "to be lucky",
      "back": "ついて　います",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "床",
      "reading": "floor",
      "back": "床[ゆか]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "転びます",
      "reading": "to fall down, fall over",
      "back": "転[ころ]びます",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "ベル",
      "reading": "bell",
      "back": "ベル",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "鳴ります",
      "reading": "to ring",
      "back": "鳴[な]ります",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "慌てて",
      "reading": "in a hurry",
      "back": "慌[あわ]てて",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "順番に",
      "reading": "in order",
      "back": "順番[じゅんばん]に",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "出来事",
      "reading": "incident",
      "back": "出来事[できごと]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "吹きます［風が〜］",
      "reading": "[wind] to blow",
      "back": "吹[ふ]きます［ 風[かぜ]が〜］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "燃えます［ごみが〜］",
      "reading": "[rubbish] to burn",
      "back": "燃[も]えます［ごみが〜］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "亡くなります",
      "reading": "to pass away (euphemistic equivalent of しにます)",
      "back": "亡[な]くなります",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "集まります［人が〜］",
      "reading": "[people] to gather",
      "back": "集[あつ]まります［ 人[ひと]が〜］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "別れます［人が〜］",
      "reading": "[people] to part, separate",
      "back": "別[わか]れます［ 人[ひと]が〜］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "します［音／声が〜］［味が〜］［においが〜］",
      "reading": "[sound/voice] to be heard, to taste, to smell",
      "back": "します［ 音[おと]／ 声[こえ]が〜］［ 味[あじ]が〜］［においが〜］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "厳しい",
      "reading": "strict, hard",
      "back": "厳[きび]しい",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "ひどい",
      "reading": "terrible, severe",
      "back": "ひどい",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "怖い",
      "reading": "frightening, horrible",
      "back": "怖[こわ]い",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "実験",
      "reading": "experiment",
      "back": "実験[じっけん]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "データ",
      "reading": "data",
      "back": "データ",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "人口",
      "reading": "population",
      "back": "人口[じんこう]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "におい",
      "reading": "smell",
      "back": "におい",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "科学",
      "reading": "science",
      "back": "科学[かがく]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "医学",
      "reading": "medicine, medical science",
      "back": "医学[いがく]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "文学",
      "reading": "literature",
      "back": "文学[ぶんがく]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "パトカー",
      "reading": "police car",
      "back": "パトカー",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "救急車",
      "reading": "ambulance",
      "back": "救急[きゅうきゅう] 車[しゃ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "賛成",
      "reading": "approval, agreement",
      "back": "賛成[さんせい]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "反対",
      "reading": "objection, opposition",
      "back": "反対[はんたい]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "大統領",
      "reading": "president",
      "back": "大統領[だいとうりょう]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "〜に　よると",
      "reading": "according to ~ (indicates the source of information)",
      "back": "〜に　よると",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "婚約します",
      "reading": "to get engaged",
      "back": "婚約[こんやく]します",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "どうも",
      "reading": "it seems that (used when making a tentative judgement)",
      "back": "どうも",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "恋人",
      "reading": "sweetheart, boyfriend, girlfriend",
      "back": "恋人[こいびと]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "相手",
      "reading": "the other person",
      "back": "相手[あいて]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "知り合います",
      "reading": "to get acquainted",
      "back": "知り合[しりあ]います",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "検証",
      "reading": "makeup (〜を　します：to put on makeup)",
      "back": "検証[けんしょう]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "世話を　します",
      "reading": "to take care of",
      "back": "世話[せわ]を　します",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "女性",
      "reading": "female, woman",
      "back": "女性[じょせい]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "男性",
      "reading": "male, man",
      "back": "男性[だんせい]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "長生き",
      "reading": "long life (〜します：to live long)",
      "back": "長生[ながい]き",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "理由",
      "reading": "reason",
      "back": "理由[りゆう]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "関係",
      "reading": "relationship",
      "back": "関係[かんけい]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "降ろします、下ろします",
      "reading": "to put down, lower, unload",
      "back": "降[お]ろします、 下[お]ろします",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "届けます",
      "reading": "to deliver",
      "back": "届[とど]けます",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "世話を　します",
      "reading": "to take care of",
      "back": "世話[せわ]を　します",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "録音します",
      "reading": "to record",
      "back": "録音[ろくおん]します",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "嫌［な］",
      "reading": "unwilling, reluctant",
      "back": "嫌[いや]［な］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "塾",
      "reading": "\u000ecram school",
      "back": "塾[じゅく]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "生徒",
      "reading": "pupil",
      "back": "生徒[せいと]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "ファイル",
      "reading": "file",
      "back": "ファイル",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "自由に",
      "reading": "freely",
      "back": "自由[じゆう]に",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "〜間",
      "reading": "for ~ (referring to duration)",
      "back": "〜 間[かん]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "いい　ことですね。",
      "reading": "That's good.",
      "back": "いい　ことですね。",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "お忙しいですか。",
      "reading": "Are you busy? (used when talking to someone senior or older)",
      "back": "お 忙[いそが]しいですか。",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "営業",
      "reading": "business, sales",
      "back": "営業[えいぎょう]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "それまでに",
      "reading": "by that time",
      "back": "それまでに",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "かまいません。",
      "reading": "It's all right. / I don't mind.",
      "back": "かまいません。",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "楽しみます",
      "reading": "to enjoy oneself",
      "back": "楽[たの]しみます",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "親",
      "reading": "parent",
      "back": "親[おや]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "小学生",
      "reading": "pupil, elementary schoolchild",
      "back": "小学生[しょうがくせい]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "ーパーセント",
      "reading": "- percent",
      "back": "ーパーセント",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "その　次",
      "reading": "next",
      "back": "その　 次[つぎ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "習字",
      "reading": "calligraphy",
      "back": "習字[しゅうじ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "普通の",
      "reading": "normal, usual",
      "back": "普通[ふつう]の",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "利用します",
      "reading": "to use",
      "back": "利用[りよう]します",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "勤めます［会社に〜］",
      "reading": "to work [for a company]",
      "back": "勤[つと]めます［ 会社[かいしゃ]に〜］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "掛けます［いすに〜］",
      "reading": "to sit on [a chair]",
      "back": "掛[か]けます［いすに〜］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "過ごします",
      "reading": "to spend (time), pass (time)",
      "back": "過[す]ごします",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "いらっしゃいます",
      "reading": "to be, go, come (respectful equivalent of います、いきます、and きます)",
      "back": "いらっしゃいます",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "召し上がります",
      "reading": "to eat, drink (respectful equivalent of たべます and のみます)",
      "back": "召し上[めしあ]がります",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "おっしゃいます",
      "reading": "to say, (one's name) is ~ (respectful equivalent of いいます)",
      "back": "おっしゃいます",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "なさいます",
      "reading": "to do (respectful equivalent of します)",
      "back": "なさいます",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "ご覧に　なります",
      "reading": "to see, look at (respectful equivalent of みます)",
      "back": "ご 覧[らん]に　なります",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "ご存じです",
      "reading": "to know (respectful equivalent of しって　います)",
      "back": "ご 存[ぞん]じです",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "あいさつ",
      "reading": "greeting, address (〜を　します：to greet, give an address)",
      "back": "あいさつ",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "旅館",
      "reading": "Japanese-style hotel or inn",
      "back": "旅館[りょかん]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "バス停",
      "reading": "bus stop",
      "back": "バス停[ばすてい]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "奥様",
      "reading": "\u000e(someone else's) wife (respectful equivalent of おくさん\u000e)",
      "back": "奥様[おくさま]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "〜様",
      "reading": "respectful equivalent of 〜さん",
      "back": "〜 様[さま]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "たまに",
      "reading": "once in a while",
      "back": "たまに",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "どなたでも",
      "reading": "anybody (respectful equivalent of だれでも)",
      "back": "どなたでも",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "〜と　いいます",
      "reading": "(one's name) is ~",
      "back": "〜と　いいます",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "ー年ー組",
      "reading": "class - of -th grade",
      "back": "ー 年[ねん]ー 組[ぐみ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "出します［熱を〜］",
      "reading": "to run [a fever]",
      "back": "出[だ]します［ 熱[ねつ]を〜］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "よろしく　お伝え　ください。",
      "reading": "Give my best regards. / Please say hello.",
      "back": "よろしく　お 伝[つた]え　ください。",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "失礼いたします。",
      "reading": "Goodbye. (humble equivalent of しつれいします)",
      "back": "失礼[しつれい]いたします。",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "経歴",
      "reading": "background",
      "back": "経歴[けいれき]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "医学部",
      "reading": "the medical department",
      "back": "医学部[いがくぶ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "目指します",
      "reading": "aim for",
      "back": "目指[めざ]します",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "進みます",
      "reading": "to go on (to graduate school)",
      "back": "進[すす]みます",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "\u000eiPS細胞",
      "reading": "induced pluripotent stem cell",
      "back": "\u000e iPS 細胞[さいぼう]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "開発します",
      "reading": "to develop, create",
      "back": "開発[かいはつ]します",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "マウス",
      "reading": "mouse",
      "back": "マウス",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "ヒト",
      "reading": "human",
      "back": "ヒト",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "受賞します",
      "reading": "to be awarded a prize",
      "back": "受賞[じゅしょう]します",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "講演会",
      "reading": "lecture meeting",
      "back": "講演[こうえん] 会[かい]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "山中伸弥",
      "reading": "Japanese medical scientist (1962-)",
      "back": "山中[やまなか] 伸[しん] 弥[や]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "ノーベル賞",
      "reading": "Nobel Prize",
      "back": "ノーベル 賞[しょう]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "参ります",
      "reading": "to go, come (humble equivalent of いきます and きます)",
      "back": "参[まい]ります",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "おります",
      "reading": "to be (humble equivalent of います)",
      "back": "おります",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "いただきます",
      "reading": "to eat, drink, receive (humble equivalent of たべます、のみます and もらいます)",
      "back": "いただきます",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "申します",
      "reading": "to say, (one's name) is ~ (humble equivalent of いいます)",
      "back": "申[もう]します",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "いたします",
      "reading": "to do (humble equivalent of します)",
      "back": "いたします",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "拝見します",
      "reading": "to see (humble equivalent of みます)",
      "back": "拝見[はいけん]します",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "存じます",
      "reading": "to get to know (humble equivalent of しります)",
      "back": "存[ぞん]じます",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "伺います",
      "reading": "to ask, hear, visit (humble equivalent of ききます and いきます)",
      "back": "伺[うかが]います",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "お目に　かかります",
      "reading": "to meet (humble equivalent of あいます)",
      "back": "お 目[め]に　かかります",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "いれます［コーヒーを〜］",
      "reading": "to make [coffee]",
      "back": "いれます［コーヒーを〜］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "用意します",
      "reading": "to prepare",
      "back": "用意[ようい]します",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "私",
      "reading": "I (humble equivalent of わたし)",
      "back": "私[わたくし]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "ガイド",
      "reading": "guide",
      "back": "ガイド",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "メールアドレス",
      "reading": "email address",
      "back": "メールアドレス",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "スケジュール",
      "reading": "schedule",
      "back": "スケジュール",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "再来週",
      "reading": "the week after next",
      "back": "再来週[さらいしゅう]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "再来月",
      "reading": "the month after next",
      "back": "再来月[さらいげつ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "再来年",
      "reading": "the year after next",
      "back": "再来年[さらいねん]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "初めに",
      "reading": "first",
      "back": "初[はじ]めに",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "江戸東京博物館",
      "reading": "Edo-Tokyo Museum",
      "back": "江戸[えど] 東京[とうきょう] 博物館[はくぶつかん]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "緊張します",
      "reading": "to become tense, be strained, be nervous",
      "back": "緊張[きんちょう]します",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "賞金",
      "reading": "prize money",
      "back": "賞金[しょうきん]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "ぎりん",
      "reading": "giraffe",
      "back": "ぎりん",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "ころ",
      "reading": "times, days",
      "back": "ころ",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "かないます［夢が〜］",
      "reading": "[dream] to be realized, come true",
      "back": "かないます［ 夢[ゆめ]が〜］",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "応援します",
      "reading": "to support",
      "back": "応援[おうえん]します",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "心から",
      "reading": "from one's heart, sincerely",
      "back": "心[こころ]から",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "感謝します",
      "reading": "to thank, be grateful",
      "back": "感謝[かんしゃ]します",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "お礼",
      "reading": "gratitude, thanks",
      "back": "お 礼[れい]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "お元気で　いらっしゃいますか。",
      "reading": "How are you doing? (respectful equivalent of おげんきですか)",
      "back": "お 元気[げんき]で　いらっしゃいますか。",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "迷惑を　かけます",
      "reading": "to cause trouble, annoyance, inconvenience",
      "back": "迷惑[めいわく]を　かけます",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "生かします",
      "reading": "to make good use of",
      "back": "生[い]かします",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "ミュンヘン",
      "reading": "Munich (in Germany)",
      "back": "ミュンヘン",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "そちら",
      "reading": "your place",
      "back": "そちら",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "どちら",
      "reading": "which one (of two things)",
      "back": "どちら",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "〜から",
      "reading": "because ~",
      "back": "〜から",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "そうですね。",
      "reading": "Well let me see. (pausing)",
      "back": "そうですね。",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "飲みます",
      "reading": "to drink alcohol",
      "back": "飲[の]みます",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "お茶",
      "reading": "tea ceremony",
      "back": "お 茶[ちゃ]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "それから",
      "reading": "and, furthermore",
      "back": "それから",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "あります",
      "reading": "to have",
      "back": "あります",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "引きます",
      "reading": "to pull",
      "back": "引[ひ]きます",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "変えます",
      "reading": "to change",
      "back": "変[か]えます",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "よく",
      "reading": "well, much",
      "back": "よく",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "チケット",
      "reading": "ticket",
      "back": "チケット",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "何",
      "reading": "what",
      "back": "何[なに]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "建物",
      "reading": "building",
      "back": "建物[たてもの]",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "front": "ええ",
      "reading": "yes",
      "back": "ええ",
      "topic": "Lesson 1"
    }
  ]
}